<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">P. Robbins Writing</title>
<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2020-02-01T23:33:27-05:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>P. Robbins</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heirlooms]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/heirlooms" />
  <id>/heirlooms</id>
  <published>2020-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2020-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>P. Robbins</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A cigarette case made of silver with an engraving of Christ crucified on the inside. His wounds smell like tobacco.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a gift to my grandfather from one of his Jazz friends, a man named Paul who said, “Everything is permitted.” They always teased him about his days as a Catholic Priest. He gave up the cloth when he was twenty-nine, took up smoking and playing the piano. His father had played the organ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He never talked about it much back then, but on Sunday mornings he could always be found at Cafe Martin, across the street from St. Mary’s Cathedral. He’d sit on the patio smoking and drinking his coffee, and he’d listen to the new priest sing the mass in Latin and to the sound of his father’s old instrument wheezing from the Cathedral’s open door. He’d sip his drink and watch the thin little wisp of white rise from the end of his coffin nail and he’d think of incense and the Holy Ghost. Occasionally, he’d look at the engraving and remember when people called him Father. Sometimes they still did, leaving the church after mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good morning, Father,” one might call to him and he’d snap the cigarette case closed and wave, smoke drifting from between his delicate fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, he moved to the country, where there were no cathedrals. He got married and had kids. Later yet, once he’d become a grandfather, he started attending mass again. He died of lung cancer a few years after that, his sins, presumably, absolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A platinum pocket watch with a broken chain. The glass was cracked once, but has since been replaced. Its tick is exceptionally loud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My great Uncle bought it to keep track of time during his walks in the Bell Woods. Before he had it, he would sometimes stroll until the sun had set and then he’d have to find his way home in the dark. He’d arrive at his parents’ house, muddy and scratched up but alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the spring and the summer, he’d walk every day in the late afternoon. The ticking of the watch would be drowned out by the chatter of bugs, the weeping of the cicada in late summer, the grasshopper’s fiddle, and the cricket’s chirp in the evenings when it was time to go home. The minutes were counted out by the clicking and the whining of the insects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In autumn, he’d pick mushrooms and listen to the crunch of dead leaves. The year he died, he found a spot where deer gathered to drink water. He’d watch them and measure out the moments of those golden afternoons by the sound of their hooves as they hopped around the stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then winter came. Everything went to sleep, and any sounds left over were consumed by the layers of indifferent snow which fell over the woods. Still he walked and listened, now to the sharp ticking of his pocket watch, each tick cutting another second into the cold, empty air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They found his body near the stream where the deer would congregate in the previous season. He was torn apart by a bear, awakened early from hibernation, hungry. I think about him in that clearing, seeing the shaggy beast emerge from the snow-covered trees. I think about the silence between each tick of his watch, as that gentle man met eyes with hungry death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bear was shot a week later, by my grandfather. The watch still keeps time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A gold fountain pen with Lapis Lazuli inlay. The initials A.B. are etched at the base.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a gift to my Aunt from her parents for graduating medical school. Her initials were A. R.  At first her parents were ashamed about the mistake with the initials, but my aunt didn’t mind. Years later they would joke that she should just marry someone with a last name that started with B, but she would never marry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was a heart surgeon. My grandparents were proud, but they would admit that they could never really understand the life my aunt chose for herself. She had always been odd. Perhaps that was why it took so long for people to notice something was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She treasured the pen, using it rarely, and then only to write love letters - if they could really be called such. They were violent blurbs, grotesque at times, scribbled by that lovely pen on loose bits of paper, half of which, I’m sure, were thrown away immediately. She signed every one A. B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She would write about a lover on the table, how she would cut open his chest and break his ribs to get at his heart. She wrote about the heat of the muscle in her fingers, the emotions pumping through his arteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One pictures her late at night, after surgery, doing paper work. She reaches for the pen, dips it in an ink well, but not before dipping it into the well of her own heart, then scratches those violent, desperate little words into the margins of her papers, her life. Soon those margins would grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She broke down during an operation, in the end, nearly costing a seventy-year-old man his life. She quit medicine after that, moved back in with her parents. She took care of them when they got older. After they died, I heard she took up writing. I don’t know if she still used the pen then. She never showed anybody what she wrote and always burned the papers afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She died alone. Only a few scraps of her writing from before her breakdown remain, faded, almost entirely illegible.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/heirlooms&quot;&gt;Heirlooms&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by P. Robbins at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;P. Robbins Writing&lt;/a&gt; on January 27, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Visionary’s Eyes]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/the-visionarys-eye" />
  <id>/the-visionarys-eye</id>
  <published>2019-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2019-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>P. Robbins</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“They didn’t think that the fire they started would ever stop burning,” Charlie’s great uncle said sombrely as they sipped hot tea and listened the squawking of the birds. “They couldn’t have known. They couldn’t see the black, sooty sea that was coming. Perhaps if they had listened to him, they might have avoided their fate–our fate–but they didn’t want to hear anyone’s ideas but their own.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlie took the book in his hands. It was not a large tome, by any means, and yet there was a weightiness to it that he couldn’t deny. The gilded title read, “The Life and Writings of Edgar Blee.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Some said he was a holy man, but they were merely fooled by his trappings. His poetry smelled of incense and the smoke of burnt offerings, but the angels he alluded to were of a world unimaginable to any saint, unimaginable, even, to those of us alive in these times, strange though they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There were those who called him a prophet. I think that’s what bothered those fire starters. They were so sure of the world that they would raise out of the wreckage, they couldn’t stand to hear someone tell them that they were fated to fail. He offered them a choice, and they drove a knife through his heart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the parrots chittered nervously and he proceeded to coo to it and stroke its feathers. Charlie opened the book and began to flip through it, until he reached a page where a large crow feather practically sprung out at him. His great uncle reached over and took it between his fingers. His hand trembled slightly. Charlie looked at the page, a poem titled, “The Azure Canopy”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…The smoke rises, our spirits escape, fly! Fly to new heights!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like so many visionaries, his vision was not quite of this world. It happens, sometimes, that a person can see so far that he fails to notice the things in his direct proximity. Edgar was different.” He ran the black, shining feather across the back of his hand. “Edgar Blee saw with perfect clarity the grey thing which sits inside us, that grey thing which, by the time the fires finally died, would be filled with ash.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlie finished the tea that was in his cup. It had gone cold. He took up the pot and refilled it, topping his great uncle’s while he was at it, for the old man seemed lost in some sad thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had survived the Melancholia which followed in the wake of the failed revolution, two whole generations prior. He was one of the last survivors of those dark days, and while most of the old men and women his age would talk endlessly about the glory of the revolution and the tragedy of its demise, he was different. Perhaps he was different the same way Edgar Blee was different. He saw things another way, which Charlie enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cockatoo fluttered, suddenly, and came to perch on Charlie’s shoulder. The room was spacious, and yet the birds all seemed to be drawn to the corner where he and his relative sat and spoke. They were clearly fond of the old man and regarded him with eyes that hinted at some alien comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edgar Blee, Charlie knew, had written much about birds and their ways. His uncle had told him about a pamphlet which detailed the life of the vulture that had eaten the old dictator’s liver. Blee had described the way the world looked from the eye of the vulture, circling overhead, watching the carnage of mankind with a hungry heart, and the subsequent visions of wasted glory that it received upon dining on the once great leader’s innards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He saw things from above,” the old man said presently, “and he had the courage to look even higher yet, but one has the sense that he could feel the anchors which keep us all down. He called them, “those ancient chains which pull us forever backwards and downwards.” I suppose, at last, we all end up in the pit.” He smiled then. “Not Edgar though.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned then and peered out of the large windows at the pale, bleeding sky, punctured by the twisted shapes of a new world–a world that probably even Edgar Blee had not foreseen–a heaven untouched by feathered wing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlie knew too of the songbooks filled with the lyrics of songbirds singing about a world beyond the clouds, a starry firmament of colours unperceived by human eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Put a large bird in a small cage and she will sing you a song of freedom,” his great uncle had once told him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lordly eagles; Knightly hawks; the virginal dove; vulture, the prophet; the priestly crow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crow, Blee’s messenger of choice, intelligent, an eater of carrion, though it didn’t seem to gorge itself the way the vulture did. It seemed more a participant in ritual, the way it partook of the flesh and the blood, the offerings of a world of violence which it accepted with cold detachment and watched with eyes filled with weird wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, they offered Blee to the crows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How many soothsayers and madmen offered up their brands of nonsense to take the place of the dictator’s madness,” the old man said after a long pause. He was feeding seeds from his palm to one of his pigeons. “Blee himself said we mustn’t blame the revolutionaries. They sought to burn nonsense from the world, establish order in the light of those wrathful flames. They could not see what he saw. There was a necessity for some nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A choice: Warm your fingers by the fire and let the flames die out, ushering in a grey, ashy era, or let oneself be consumed by the blaze and free the spirit that it might rise to heaven and above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where they saw a means for illumination, he saw the churning seed of destruction at the core of the fire, and of what it was capable: annihilation or ascension.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Edgar Blee was a lunatic,” Charlie’s father had told him once, when he tried to talk to him about great uncle Thomas’ fascination with the poet and writer, “And a zealot too. Good riddance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about the man who shot the crow that ate Blee’s eyes?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He was probably a loon too,” his father said. “Those were different times.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The air in the room reeked of musty feathers, but the warmth of the sun through the windows and the heat of the teacup in the palm of Charlie’s hand was pleasant as he listened to his great uncle recount the death of Edgar Blee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He had supported the revolutionaries, but they denounced him like they did so many others,” Thomas said. His eyes were clear. “They started more fires than they could keep track of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We tried to hide him. Under the dictatorship we had gotten good at hiding, but the revolutionaries knew the ways, they were as full of guile as the rest of us back then, and they snatched him up. He was made an example of. They would not tolerate nonsense, especially nonsense which denied their grand project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We recovered the body, and gave it to the crows, just as he had requested. We offered him up in hopes that they would bring him to the heavens he had only seen but never touched. His eyes, those eyes once so full of vision, were the first to go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And that was when someone fired the shot?” Charlie interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s right,” Thomas nodded. “We never found out who, or why, but the crow which ate his eyes was shot right out of the air.” He held the long black feather aloft. “We recovered it, but it was no use. Those of us who were closest to Blee were each given a single feather.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s too bad,” Charlie admitted, “his eyes never made it to the heavens they saw.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” his great uncle agreed. “But his tongue, that silver little muscle, now sings with the songbirds, and his fingertips may yet brush against the firmament. His heart too, though it went in several pieces, I believe, beats on within the larger heart of that far off world most likely never to be seen again.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/the-visionarys-eye&quot;&gt;The Visionary’s Eyes&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by P. Robbins at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;P. Robbins Writing&lt;/a&gt; on April 04, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jack and The Wheel of Fortune]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/jack-and-the-wheel-of-fortune" />
  <id>/jack-and-the-wheel-of-fortune</id>
  <published>2019-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2019-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>P. Robbins</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack had had a bad day. It was the kind of day that put a shadow on you – darkened your whole past and any future you could envision. Jack’s life was, admittedly, not to be envied, but there was some good to it. He had experienced his small share of happiness at times; was even in possession of a few memories over which, like the small embers which remained after a bonfire, he could warm the cold fingers of his misery and make it all  a little more bearable. Not today though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presently, Jack sat in his usual spot at the Rooster, trying to drink away his sorrows. Somehow, he hardly had the energy even for that. He sipped his beer irregularly, as though he kept forgetting it was there. What little he drank hardly did much to take the edge off. His nerves were wrought. He felt his spirit frayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He just kept going over the scene from earlier that afternoon in his mind. He had been in a good place, comfortable at that high-stakes table. He had felt, for the first time in his life really, that he had earned his spot somewhere above all the squalor and the mediocrity that had been his world for as long as he could remember. There had even been a moment at some point where he had felt sure that the stars had aligned, that his whole life, all the trials and the failures, hadn’t been for nothing – that everything he’d ever experienced or done had led him to this place of glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it had all come tumbling down. Just like it always did. Directly after his brutal defeat he had found, for a little while, some small comfort in his outrage that he had lost due to clear and obvious cheating on the part of Donny Carmichael – a known liar and a thief – but this comfort was doomed not to last. So what, Donny had cheated? They were all cheaters in one way or another. Jack had himself managed only to buy in after months of pulling robberies in the alleyways of the Strip. The game itself was just one short round in that never ending game of cards in which all the dirt money of the world passed from one dirty hand to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact remained: Jack had been unable to do anything. He had lost all the money he had spent months saving up, and then some. It was one thing to lose what he’d saved, but quite another to be in debt now to Mr. Gabriel. That last failure had been all due to his pride. He had no one to blame for that but himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack pushed his half-empty glass of beer away, towards the dim red candle that sat in the middle of his two-person table. He surveyed the room absentmindedly, watched his fellow down-and-outers coldly. Normally, he might have felt a kinship for the drunks and the degenerates which populated the tiny establishment, but the shadow allowed him no such comfort. His one-time comrades had turned to strangers. There were no friends – a friend was just a person who hadn’t found quite the right opportunity to cheat you yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack shook his head. No, he couldn’t quite believe that. Even he wasn’t so pathetically cynical, and ever unpredictable chance seemed ready to confirm it for him by just that moment sending in one of his few remaining friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take long for Dusty to spot Jack moping at his usual corner, even with only one eye. Of course, Dusty had heard about what had happened at the high-stakes game. Word travelled fast on the Strip, where info on who was up and who was down was one of the most sought commodities. Jack was well liked among his fellow thieves, and there were none who were pleased to hear that he had been marked by Mr. Gabriel – least of all Dusty who could still recall with clarity how he had originally taken young Jack under his wing nearly fifteen years ago when Jack was only fourteen years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, bud,” Dusty said, pulling up a chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey,” Jack replied, not really looking at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusty gestured to the barkeep. “Let’s get you something a little stronger, eh? I’m buying.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack did not protest. He was rotating the tiny red candle between his fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two shots were placed up on the edge of the bar within arms reach of Dusty who, leaning back in his chair, grabbed them and placed one in front of his friend. “Cheers,” he said, and they each downed their drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards they were quiet for a while. Dusty was waiting for Jack to speak first, and eventually he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I keep thinking about what I could have done with that money,” he said. “I could have started a business or something. We could have made something of ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusty laughed, though not with unkindness. “You know what happens to businesses,” he said. “Sometimes they fail. There’s risk no matter what. You’ve got to spend money to make money, like they say, but sometimes you spend money and you don’t get anything back. That’s just life.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah and sometimes you spend money and end up indebted to Mr. Gabriel,” Jack said, bitterly. “Is that life, Dusty?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusty shrugged. “I’ll admit, that’s a hell of a hand you’ve been dealt, bud.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack shook his head. “I wasn’t dealt it. I did it to myself. I was a fool. I got too full of myself, thought I could turn it around. I lost my self-control.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusty looked hard at him. “Now that, I know, is not true. That isn’t you, Jack, losing self-control. You don’t know what it’s like to really lose self-control. Maybe you weren’t as disciplined as you could have been, but in the end you just miscalculated, that’s all, that and some bad luck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It wasn’t bad luck,” Jack said. “It was Donny Carmichael and his damned cheating.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was bad luck that landed Donny Carmichael at your table,” Dusty retorted. “That was out of your control. But you’re still in control of yourself.” He sighed. “I remember when I was at my worst. If you’d seen that, you would have seen a man who had truly no-self control. I tell you, bud, there is evil in this world. Mr. Gabriel is one evil son of a bitch, but he can be dealt with. The worst kind of evil is the evil in yourself – the kind that makes you do things you wish you could stop yourself from doing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack had heard it all before. He’d learned everything he knew about card-playing from Dusty. Nobody knew cards better than him, but his knowledge had come at a price. He was a slave to the game, in body, mind and spirit. People had told Jack about what he’d been like, only a few years before he’d met him – one of those desolate kinds with hollow eyes, ever seeking the perfect hand. He’d come close to annihilation after ending up in a similar situation to the one that Jack was in now – with Mr. Gabriel as well, no less. In the end, he’d managed to claw his way back to life, losing his right eye in the process. It was a small price to pay, by Dusty’s own admission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t realize it was a competition,” Jack said in regard to their misfortunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m just saying. Mr. Gabriel can be dealt with, as bad as he is, he’s still just another man looking to get his.” He scratched his pocked cheek below his glass eye, seemingly unconsciously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on, Dust,” Jack replied. “Don’t pretend like I’m not as good as dead.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re too young to be so forlorn,” Dusty said sharply. “Now come on, fine, we’re not rich as hell like we thought we’d be, and fair enough, it might take years for you to pay back Mr. Gabriel, but you can pay him back. He’ll only come after you if you try to run off, believe me. As long as you don’t do that, you should be fine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And how the hell am I supposed to pay him back, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ll talk to Esme,” Dusty started and Jack groaned. “No, no, listen to me – we’ll talk to Esme, see if we can get a few scores, then we’ll go back to lower-stakes. I’m not saying it’ll be quick. We’re going to have to hustle again for a while, but that’s just life, Jack. We’ve got to do what we’ve got to in order to survive. You hear me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack sighed. “I don’t know if Esme will agree,” he said. “She seemed pretty put off by the end of it, like she was relieved we weren’t going to be working together anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You just let me do the talking,” Dusty smiled. “It’s that compassion of hers. She’s got more of it for people like us than the marks, believe me.” He rose from his chair then. “Come on, let’s go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What? Now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, now!” Dust exclaimed. “Listen, bud, you’re in a hell of a jam. I can tell you’re licked, so all the more reason to get to work. That’ll make you feel better, I promise.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fine,” Jack said, getting to his feet. Though he didn’t want to admit it, Dusty was right, he was feeling a little better now that he had something to do – some course of action. He patted his pocket and felt the weight of his knife there – an old bone-handled knife with little skulls engraved into the side of the blade. It was a longtime companion of his. He might have had to sell it to buy himself some time, but now he felt it better put to use in his work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Gabriel, while not being the most powerful person in the city, or even on the strip, was still well known by all. He was a middling member of the family, and like anyone with any authority in that group, there were always rumours about him. He, like many of his brothers and sisters, was said to have an interest in the occult and this, apparently, had some influence on how he dealt with people he opposed. There were the usual stories of ritualistic hits and people going missing under strange circumstances. In any case, it was a fact that he was not someone you wanted to owe money to, due to his penchant for cruelty. People said that Dusty had gotten off easy with the beating that had had left him with a still perceptible limp in his gait and a missing eye. There were those that claimed Dusty had been shown some small mercy because Mr. Gabriel respected his card playing – one of the few skills he showed a real admiration for, besides, so the stories went, butchery. Nobody could confirm one way or another, though. Rumours abounded of other, not so merciful cases in which Mr. Gabriel himself had peeled strips of flesh from dealers hands who had cheated him, and burned the soles of the feet of people who owed him money (supposedly to put a bit of heat in their step, he would say).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such stories circled Jack’s head, despite his effort to keep them at bay, as he walked with Dusty down the Strip. The sky was inky, no trace of any stars, drowned as they were in the false light of the crowded Main Street. He watched the old man weave with some effort through the crowds of drunken tourists, his slight limp a hindrance, and thought of what he himself had experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had asked Dusty on a few occasions, usually while they were drunk, about what Mr. Gabriel had done to him. In particular, he had always been curious how Dusty had lost his eye. Despite people calling it a mercy, he couldn’t imagine how terrible it must have been to have someone cut out one of your eyes. Eventually Dusty had corrected him on this misunderstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nah, they just beat me so bad my eye socket cracked and punctured it. Probably they could have saved my eye had they got me to a hospital on time, but the whole thing was just sloppy. I was out of it, anyway. It was my hip that hurt the worst, I couldn’t even tell there was anything wrong with my eye. Both of them were so swelled up, I couldn’t see anything. Eventually I fell asleep, next thing I knew I was in the hospital and they’d already removed the damn thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presently the two men turned into an alleyway, abandoning the flashy lights of the Strip’s main attractions – card-halls and casinos, billiards clubs, bars and strip joints, the occasional diner that had once hosted this celebrity or that – and plunged into the city’s more peripheral draws: dens of smoke, parlours of night people looking for some company, lodges for those with an esoteric bend, and of course, the fortune tellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They stopped in front of the small store-front, their faces cartoonish in the neon blue and red from the sign which read: Palm Reading, Crystal Ball, Tarot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on,” Dusty said, lumbering with some effort up the stair case and through the glass door which rang a rusty bell with a hollow timbre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme appeared, stepping through the beaded curtain behind the counter with an alluring smile that instantly faded the moment she laid eyes on Dusty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Esmeralda, darling!” Dusty declared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme’s eyes shifted from Dusty to Jack and back again. “What are you two doing here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why, we’re here for a palm-reading! What do you think?” Dusty said with a grin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme narrowed her eyes at him, and then turned to Jack. “I guess I deserve that. There’s no point in playing dumb with you. I heard what happened, Jack, sorry.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme was the kind of woman whose age was hard to tell. She was dark, in complexion, hair, and eye, and therefore obscured in a way. In truth, she was middle-aged, though the only thing which indicated this was her voice – hoarse from years of chain smoking. She used this to her advantage with her clients though, playing up the rasp when she pretended to be possessed by the spirits of dead loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Things didn’t really go the way we hoped they would,” Dusty said. “So it looks like Jack and I have to get back to work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We had a deal, Dusty,” Esme said. “You know how I feel about this kind of work. We said this would be it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on, Esme, I’m asking you as a friend,” Dusty replied. “Our boy is in a pinch, as you well know. We just need some funds to get us started. I might have come here asking for a loan – Lord knows you made off like a bit of a bandit yourself on account of our arrangement – but I respect your work too much for that. Just a couple of scores, that’s all I’m asking for, just something to get old Jackie boy here back on his feet, what do you say?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme bit her lip. She looked concernedly at Jack, who avoided meeting her gaze, and then back at Dusty. “It’s not right. I don’t feel right sending my clients into the mouth of the lion, so to speak.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh come on, we’ve talked about this,” Dusty said. “You’re already pretty much robbing them -and I don’t mean that in a bad way. The people who come here, the people who wander off the Strip like, in a way they’re looking to get robbed. It’s part of the experience! We’re practically doing them a service.” He laughed then, but it felt a little forced. It was true that they’d talked about this all before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack’s eyes wandered to some of the posters on the wall depicting a selection of the major arcana. He regarded the Wheel of Fortune lined with people that were tied to it – at the top, a smiling, bound man met the sun and the clouds, an illusion of freedom, while at the bottom a man who could have been his brother was being ground into the flames of Hell. Esme followed his gaze and a sad look came over her. She sighed heavily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fine, but just a couple!” She agreed at last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, Esme, you’ve got a heart after all! I don’t care what anyone says,” Dusty exclaimed with a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme scoffed. “Just give me a second.” She produced a thick ledger and opened it up. “I’ve got three appointments tonight – two of them are regulars, and I would never feed them to you, but they don’t have anything worth stealing anyway. The third is a new client, I don’t know much about her. Other than that there may be a few walk-ins.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, we’ve got nothing better to do tonight, do we, Jack?” Dusty grinned at his younger friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Lounge then?” Jack replied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sounds good to me,” Dusty nodded. He looked at Esme. “When’s that new client of yours?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She’s coming at midnight,” Esme said, still seeming resigned about the whole thing. “She was a little odd on the phone.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A rich eccentric,” Dusty said, rubbing his grey chin. “Could be promising. You know how to reach us, Esme. Let’s go, Jack.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack began to follow Dusty out of the small shop, but stopped briefly and turned around. “Thanks, Esme,” he said, still not really able to meet her eyes. “I really appreciate you doing this for me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t mention it, kid,” Esme told him. The sad look had not left her eyes. “Sorry again, about your big loss.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack shrugged and stepped towards the door. “The Wheel of Fortune spins on, I guess,” he said, and stepped out into the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many a night Jack and Dusty had spent at the Lounge, just a block down the side street from Esme’s shop. It was an underground joint and admission was by invitation only, making the clientele almost entirely locals. They were friends with the owner, a rotund and taciturn gentleman by the name of Johnny who ran a tight ship. He was happy to pass along messages from Esme to them, when and if an opportunity for a score arose. Dusty let him know the deal as soon as they entered, and he nodded understandingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry to hear about what happened, Jack,” Johnny said through his thick moustache, his face fixed into his permanently neutral expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks,” Jack replied. He admired Johnny, admired the way he seemed to meet everything with clear comprehension and the talent he apparently had for holding on to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just a heads up though,” Johnny said, leaning in conspiratorially. “Donny Carmichael.” He motioned towards the other end of the Lounge where, sure enough, the snake was seated at a low-stakes game and chatting up a couple of the night people who always lined the walls of the place waiting for someone to win it big and throw a little of the earnings their way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks, Johnny,” Dusty answered for Jack, noticing that a stray cat had apparently caught his friends tongue. He pulled Jack away from the bar. “Just ignore him,” he whispered as Jack stared hard at the man who had cost him everything. “It’s not worth it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They took a seat at the table closest to the exit and waited. Occasionally some of the night people who they were familiar with would try to come up and give Jack their condolences, having heard about his loss, but Dusty waved them away, sensing how each time it was mentioned Jack’s eyes were drawn to Donny who still sat laughing at the cards table. Despite his cheating, he had not walked away with any winnings, but neither was he in debt, and seeing him live freely and without fear of having his legs broken by Mr. Gabriel’s men filled Jack with a silent, aching rage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just forget about it, Jack, seriously,” Dusty told him. “We’ve got to be ready to go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Donny finished up with his game and rose from his table. He grabbed one of the night people, a young lady that Jack had once enjoyed the company of himself, back when he had had the funds, and made his way towards the exit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Damn it,” Dusty muttered, but there was nothing to be done. Donny spotted the two of them and told his companion for the evening to hang back a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, gentlemen, it’s good to see you,” he said as he approached their table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just keep walking, Donny,” Dusty said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Say, Jack, sorry about today,” Donny said, slicking back his dark, oily hair with a ring studded hand. “It’s a shame about that bad hit you took, but I sure hope there’s no hard feelings.” Jack stared into the young man’s beady eyes. “Put it there,” he said, extending his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack said nothing. Almost unconsciously he felt his hand slip down to the knife in his pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nobody here is going to shake your hand, you arrogant, dumb prick,” Dusty said, and Jack would later feel some surprise at the anger in the old mans voice. “You’ve got no respect for the cards. Take a hike.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey now, there’s no need for insults,” Donny replied, mock hurt written on his face. “You know, I really feel for our friend here. I was even thinking about putting in a good word with Mr. Gabriel on his behalf, maybe to buy him some time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?” Jack said, his expression snapping into one of outrage. “What do you mean by that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Didn’t you know?” Donny asked. “I’ve been working for Mr. Gabriel for a while now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just get lost, Donny,” Dusty exclaimed now, shifting his position slightly to put himself between him and Jack. “God damn it, just go!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fine, fine,” Donny replied, and then motioned for his companion. As he walked through the exit he said, “I’ll let Mr. Gabriel know you’re hard at work getting him his money!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry about your loss, Jack,” the girl said softly, following Donny out of the Lounge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack just sat there with his fists clenched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess now we know how he got away with his cheating,” Dusty muttered. He tugged at his grey whiskers and grimaced. “God, what a…” he trailed off and sighed. “No words, there’s nothing we can do about it, Jack. This just means there’s definitely no way we can mess with him now. You’re just going to have to accept it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack continued to sit in silence. Eventually Dusty ordered them some drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s almost midnight,” he said, bringing the drinks back to their table. “Let’s finish these and then get sharp. I’ve got a good feeling about this new client of Esme’s.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack downed his drink and exhaled shakily. “Alright,” he said, the rage slowly draining from his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after midnight, the call came. Johnny made a gesture from the bar and Dusty rose, but he shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She wants to talk to Jack, she says.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusty shrugged. “Well, go on then, bud.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack went to the bar and took the receiver from Johnny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Esme? What’s up?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen, Jack, I’m not telling Dusty this because I know he’d just go either way,” she started, “but I’ve got a bad feeling about that lady.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So it’s a no go, then?” Jack said, deflated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, here’s the thing… Okay, she’s got a lot of money – I mean a lot of it – but it’s like I said, I’ve got a real bad feeling, Jack. She said some weird stuff and she gave me the creeps.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack understood now why she was bringing this to him and not Dusty. Dusty would have just laughed it off, but Jack was not in the habit of taking things lightly when someone was trying to help him out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re sure she’s got money?” He asked evenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s the only reason I’m calling you about it,” Esme said. “Money like that, the money I saw with my own eyes, that could help you out of the bind you’re in but, to be totally honest, I’m not sure it’s worth it. I mean it, Jack, there’s something really wrong with this woman.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What does she look like?” Jack asked after a pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, Jack,” Esme replied. He could hear the hesitation in her voice. “She’s older, maybe in her fifties or sixties, thin, she’s wearing a nice black dress, not revealing in the slightest, long black gloves, and a red silk scarf. You can’t miss her, she’ll probably be wearing sunglasses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sunglasses?” Jack repeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told you, she’s weird,” Esme said, “She wore them the whole time she was with me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alright, thanks, Esme.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you really going to go after her?” Esme asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t exactly have time to mull it over,” Jack said, “If she’s got the kind of money you’re implying, well, it’s like you said. I’m in a bind.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme sighed shakily. “Alright, Jack, just make sure you and Dusty call me when it’s over.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Seriously?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I’m serious!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay,” Jack agreed. “Which way did she go?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme told him, and then wished them luck. He hung up and then motioned for Dusty to get up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s go,” he told the old man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s on?” Dusty asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack nodded, and then relayed the conversation with Esme. Unsurprisingly, Dusty just laughed. “This town, I tell you,” he said, “Just a bunch of superstitious drunks – it must be something in the water.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take long for the pair of thieves to figure out where the mystery woman had gone. They considered it fortunate that she was apparently not heading towards the Strip, but rather deeper into the network of side streets and alleyways of the city. Once they spotted her, and saw the wealth she wore on her sleeve, the challenge became simply finding a way to ambush her before some other lowlifes got their claws in her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She is an odd duck,” Dusty commented from the shadows of an alleyway as they watched her proceed beneath the flickering streetlight of a desolate backstreet. She was just as Esme had described, sunglasses and all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They ducked out and took a parallel street, advancing ahead far enough to give them some time to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You ready?” Dusty said, taking out his small, snub-nosed revolver. Jack honed his knife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think so.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They emerged from the darkness. The sound of Dusty’s gun cocking echoed in the empty street. “Hold it, lady,” he said. “Come forward, nice and easy. We don’t want to have to hurt you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusty proceeded to give his usual spiel. In a way, Jack suspected that Dusty liked to view himself as some kind of gentleman thief – never rude or cruel, if he could avoid it. Jack, on the other hand, had no taste for the business. He had always thought of it as an unfortunate but necessary stepping stone in order to procure the funds for his real trade – cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally people reacted in one of two ways – they were either paralyzed with fear, or immediately fell into hysterics. Dusty had long ago worked out with Esme a profile for the type of marks she could send their way – usually it was rich older ladies, like this one, but this time was different. It was hard to tell, admittedly, with those sunglasses obscuring a good portion of her face, but she seemed far too calm. No, up close, Jack could tell exactly what Esme had meant about her. There was something off. He was always nervous anytime he had to rob someone, but this time his nervousness quickly escalated to fear and then to panic. It took everything he had not to just turn and run, even Dusty seemed a little shaken up when the old bird showed no hint of concern at being robbed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nice and easy,” Dusty kept saying, to the point where Jack wondered if he was saying it more to himself than their mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closer she got to them, the more put off Jack was feeling. Under the light of the faulty street lamp, it became clear that she was wearing heavy makeup and lipstick. It seemed to Jack like she was wearing a mask. The way she moved, too, was strange and disturbing. She was very thin and with each step it was like her small, frail body was under enormous strain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There we are,” Dusty said, and Jack noted the sweat on his temple shimmering in the dim light. “Now hand over your purse and any other valuables you’ve got.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ah,” the lady suddenly said, and her voice felt harsh in Jack’s ears, like grinding metal, “It’s my money you’re after, is it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusty let out something which sounded like a cough in an effort to steady himself and Jack could tell that he too was reeling from the awful sound of her voice. “Ahem, yes, we’re not about that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, but I have many gifts, you know,” she said, her words crunching painfully in Jack’s head. They were filled with something like static. Had Dusty not been standing firmly at his side, he would have turned and run right that moment. “If fortune is what you seek, there are better ways. I can give you the means to obtain a great treasure.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Money will suffice,” Dusty managed to reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She held out her purse. “Do you know the name of this city?” She asked, but neither replied. “No, you don’t know who really runs this place. I can feel Him, beneath the earth, turning, the wheel and the serpent: Sha-ishrasharshala.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack clenched his teeth and tasted iron, moaning slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut up, you goddamned schizo!” Dusty exclaimed, no trace of his gentleman thief persona remaining. He gestured with his gun. “Take her purse, Jack!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the hell, man!” Jack said, sputtering, half enraged by Dusty’s demand and half from him so carelessly using his real name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just do it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come here, boy,” the lady said, smiling. He could not see her eyes. “Take my money, if that’s all you want.” She seemed to sway awkwardly in the shadows, like a drunk, though her words were lucid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut up!” Dusty exclaimed again, holding his free hand to the side of his head as though his skull were about to roll off his shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack inched his way forward, holding his knife out in front of him. He couldn’t think clearly through the static. He kept telling himself, just grab the purse and get out, grab the purse and get out, and his body, reacting more to the words in his head than anything else, did as it was told. He snatched the purse and then backed off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ll want these as well?” She asked, softer now, holding up a gloved hand on which she wore several rings and a silver bracelet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take them off,” Dusty ordered, his jaw muscles flexing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s just go,” Jack pleaded quietly. “Come on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” he said, not taking his eyes off the lady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Very well.” She removed the glove from her other hand and the two men gasped. At first it seemed like the veins in her hand and wrist were just dark, then Jack reasoned that it was simply a trick of the eye, but even in the dim light of the alley it was clear that something black was writhing beneath her pale, transparent skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack cried out. He tried to turn and run, nearly dropping the purse in the process, but Dusty grabbed his arm. “Keep it together, bud!” He glared at the lady. “And you! Hurry up, hand them over.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She removed her rings, one at a time, and then carefully unfastened her bracelet. Jack could not bear to look at her exposed skin. His mind was reeling, he felt exhausted and sick and wanted nothing more than to go home. Dusty looked at him like he was going to tell him to grab the jewellery. Jack had never seen him like this before – he was frenzied, it seemed to him. Seeing Jack in the state that he was, something softened in Dusty once more. “Wait here,” he whispered to him, and then went himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come here Mr. Thief,” the lady cooed, “come and take them. I have much to offer you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened next happened was too fast for Jack to really see. She handed Dusty the rings and the bracelet, but before he had a full grasp of them she quickly grabbed him with her glove-less hand. He screamed – not a scream of fear, but a scream of agony. He dropped his gun and with his newly freed hand clawed at his good eye while he tried to wrench free the arm she held fast to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack, shocked, dropped the purse and, to his surprise, in a moment of unexpected bravery charged the pair and tackled them to the ground. There was a struggle which he managed to wrestle himself from briefly. Dusty, freed from the woman’s grasp, still cried out and now clawed at his eye and his ears. Jack looked from him to the lady who, in the struggle had lost her sunglasses, and what he saw in her now exposed eyes unleashed a torrent of ice water in his veins. All fight turned to flight, and he took off yelling at the top of his lungs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Help! Someone, please, help me!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He could hear her pursuit. Her voice followed him down the alley like a ghost of static and broken glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gifts! So many gifts! Take them! All the treasure of the earth can be yours!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned only once, and seeing the she was within arms reach, burning two holes into the back of his head with those damned, writhing eyes, he screamed and immediately tripped over a discarded trashcan, sending himself sprawling upon the grimy alley floor. Then she was upon him, her face pressed up against his, her fingers prying their way into his mouth. He could smell the powdery make-up, the thick perfume, and something beneath it all, something not unlike smell of the raw sewage which sometimes crept up into the streets from the sewer grates stamped with the city’s seal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He awoke screaming in the predawn light, his arms and legs thrashing. The bum, who had been stooped over him, caught a foot in his shin and toppled over shouting, “Good Lord! You’re alive!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack went on hollering until his voice ran out, which didn’t take long, and his already exhausted limbs had used up the last reserves of his energy. His eyes rolled in his skull for a while as he gasped until he was forced to close them tight. When he opened them once more he felt himself back in control, somewhat. The bum had taken off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack’s head felt as though someone had tried to split it in half, and there was a loud ringing in his ears. He wheezed as he tried to lift himself up and get his bearings. Bits and pieces slowly started coming back to him, each more terrible than the last. At last he had to try and stop himself from remembering. For the moment, his only concern was finding Dusty. He stumbled down the alley, holding his arm out for balance. For the briefest moment he saw the darkness writhing beneath his skin and he screamed hoarsely and blinked – it was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get a hold of yourself,” he breathed, and he managed to, for a bit, until he found Dusty’s body in a pool of stagnant blood – then he collapsed once more, choking back a sob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The streets were spinning around him. He could not tell which way was was up and which down, and all the while the ringing in his ears was getting worse – lowering in pitch, but not in volume. He wiped the tears away from his eyes and looked one way and then another. There was no one out yet. Night had hardly changed to morning, save for the dim glow on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get it together, get it together,” he told himself after a while. He knew he couldn’t stick around. Dusty wouldn’t want him getting caught up in this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He felt sick and strained beyond belief. He tried to think of his next steps – he wanted more than anything to go home and sleep, but he couldn’t get the face of the lady out of his mind, her eyes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme. He would go to Esme. She was involved, she would need to know what happened. He clung to this goal desperately, it alone got him back on his feet. He looked once more at Dusty’s mangled corpse, lying right where he’d left him when he’d run away, and then got moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time he made it to Esme’s shop, the ringing in his ears had evolved entirely. It was no longer inside of his head, but sounded, rather, as though it were coming from somewhere outside of him. So too had it gone from a high pitch ringing to a deep and harsh rumbling, almost grinding sound. It forced him, the worse it got, to hold his palms up to his ears in an attempt to block it out. He groaned as he shuffled up the stairs and through Esme’s door. He was in too much pain to even realize how odd it was that she had left it open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Esme!” He tried to call out. “Esme!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From behind the beaded curtain he could see a faint light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Esme?” He stepped around the front counter and through the beads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room was dark and curtained, at the centre a table, the top of which was covered in carved arcane symbols, was knocked over – the shattered remains of a crystal ball were scattered to one end of the room. At the back, the curtains had been ripped down and beyond that came the source of the light – Esme herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She sat hunched against the back wall. She had pulled her knees up to her chest with one arm, and the other laid limp at her side, holding in its fingers a shard of the crystal ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Esme?” Jack wheezed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked at him. Light poured out of her eyes towards him. He beheld a halo wrapped around her black, messy hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My God,” he murmured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She came back for me,” Esme said. Tears were rolling down her cheeks, staining them with illumination. “She said she had a gift for me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We never should have messed with her, Esme,” Jack said, “You were right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can hear it, can’t you?” Esme asked. She wasn’t really looking at him, he could see. “You can hear it, grinding beneath the city? The Old Thing – Sha-Ishrasharshala.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, Esme,” Jack said, feeling the tears now burning in his own eyes. “Please.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can see it, now, can’t you? My spirit, burning at the edge.” She closed her eyes and it was dark once more. “I can feel it, brimming over.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stop, Esme,” Jack pleaded, his voice shaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m not worthy of this gift,” she said, and then plunged the shard of glass into her throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack scrambled to try and stop her, but the blood was coming too fast. He was bathed in it, trying to pry the shard from her fingers. He watched her choke – watched the light in her eyes fade until there was only fear, and then nothing; Only silence and the harsh rumbling from below growing louder yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim had always been an early riser. It was easier for him, being a man without vice, one of the many benefits afforded to him by his choice of lifestyle, and not even the best by far. The best, by his reckoning, was the respect it earned him from some of his colleagues and the fear from others. The fear was a good thing, a necessary thing, being an enforcer of Mr. Gabriel’s. It was good to keep people on their toes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this particular morning, however, it was his early rising which would benefit him the most, as he was probably one of the only people awake in that nocturnal city to see Jack wandering in the outskirts. He was sitting in a diner – the only one he knew that was open at that hour – sipping a decaffeinated coffee, watching the sun rise on the grey and grimy streets, when he spotted the lumbering, blood-soaked figure emerge from an alleyway. He nearly choked on his coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, Mitch,” he said, calling to the owner of the diner – another early bird like himself - “Come take a look at this!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitch joined him, wiping his hands on his apron, and cursed when he laid eyes on the bloodied, dazed-looking Jack shambling down the sidewalk. “Isn’t that Jack?” he said. “What’s he doing in this part of town, and looking like that no less?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” Slim replied and got up, “But I guess I won’t be able to enjoy my coffee this morning.” He fished a bit of cash out of his pocket and placed it on the table – he was not one to skip out on a bill – and told Mitch, “Give Donny Carmichael a call and tell him to meet me on the Strip in front of the Royale, he’s going to want to see this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure thing,” Mitch replied, taking up the cash and admiring his tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside, Slim quickly caught up with Jack, but made sure to keep his distance. “Hey Jack!” He shouted. “I’m talking to you, Jack!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly, the bloody young man turned to face him. His eyes were distant and pale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the hell happened to you, fella? Where in the goddamn do you thing you’re going?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can hear it,” Jack croaked, though it didn’t seem like he was saying it to Slim. “The serpent and the wheel, grinding beneath the city.” He smiled faintly. “There is treasure in this place.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim was baffled by his words. He had heard junkie-speak before, as he called it, but Jack was supposed to be clean, as far as he knew about the kid, and there was something grating about his voice besides. Still, he picked up on that last bit. “You better hope there is, kid, ‘cause Mr. Gabriel’s going to be expecting some money from you pretty soon.” He licked his lips, as was his nervous habit – an ironic tick, he had been told, for a man supposedly without vices. “You aren’t thinking about leaving town, are you, Jack?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You have a strange heart,” Jack replied, at last addressing the short, clean cut man before him. “Your spirit is cold and severe. There is use for you, in this place of fortune.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim was looking at the blood on Jack – there was a lot of it, and he realized, seeing it up close now, that it seemed fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you got any weapons on you, Jack?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack slowly pulled out the knife from his pocket and Slim quickly reached for his gun. “I’m going to get you to drop that right now,” he told him, and noticed that there was no blood on it. “Anything else?” He asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack shook his head no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m going to pat you down, just in case, no sudden movements, you hear me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack did as he was told. Slim found nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alright, why don’t we go for a little drive, eh, buddy?” Slim said and was relieved to see Jack comply. “I think Mr. Gabriel would like to meet with you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donny was not pleased to be woken up early. His companion had already left sometime not long after midnight, and he had been looking forward to sleeping in late. He was angry at first, until Mitch told him what it was about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s Jack,” Mitch said through the receiver. “I don’t know what the hell that kid’s trying to pull, but it ain’t pretty. Something crazy is about to go down. Slim wants you to meet him outside the Royale.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Donny got dressed and tried to make sense of things. He felt a little worried. He had not expected Jack to snap or try to pull something, and Mr. Gabriel was unpredictable enough to put the blame on him for taking it too far with the guy. He cursed under his breath as he buttoned up his shirt and left his apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later he was out on the side of the street. The sun was just starting to peak above the horizon, casting long, dark shadows down the Strip. Slim pulled up shortly and stepped out of his car. Donny tried to look inside the car, but the windows were too tinted to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s in there,” Slim told him. “Jack,” he clarified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the hell is going on, Slim?” Donny hissed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing good,” Slim said, cool as always. “The kid is a mess. I think he may have killed someone or something, not sure.” He narrowed his eyes at Donny. “You didn’t mess with him at all last night, did you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No! Of course not,” Donny answered, trying to conceal the shakiness in his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I sure hope that’s true,” Slim said, still glaring at the oily young man, “Because it’s looking like Mr. Gabriel might not get his money, at this rate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donny said nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No you better go in there and let him know that…” he trailed off. “On second thought, I’d better go talk to the boss. You stay here and keep an eye on our boy, you got it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fine, fine,” Donny said, no longer able to hide the fact that he was shaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Slim was gone, Donny opened the door of the car and looked in – he nearly shrieked when he saw Jack’s bloody face staring back at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the hell, Jack? What do you think you’re doing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack just smiled back at him. “Your spirit is made of loose threads,” he said in a strangled whisper. “The winds of this city will tear you to pieces, pretty soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donny slammed the door and cursed loudly as he ran his fingers through his hair, nearly ripping it out of his skull. Slim returned from the hotel and beckoned to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mr. Gabriel wants to see him,” he said quietly. “Help me get him inside – discretely, Donny, if you please.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They took the service elevator up to the top floor, the suites. All the while Jack stared at Donny who couldn’t help but tell there was something wrong with his eyes. He whispered things intermittently: “You serve no purpose here.” “There is a worm in your heart.” “You will never see the treasure. Fortune hides itself from your eyes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Goddamn it, shut up!” Donny shouted after a while. He looked at Slim. “What the hell is the matter with him? Is he high or something? And whose blood is that anyway?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim just shook his head. “We’ll just let Mr. Gabriel deal with it,” was all he said, much to Donny’s fury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once on the top floor, they walked the complacent Jack to Mr. Gabriel’s suite. He seemed not the least concerned about his present fate. They rang the buzzer and were let in by a servant who proceeded to guide them to Mr. Gabriel’s large office. “Try to keep the blood off the rug,” the servant said, a tone of futility bleeding into his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entering the office, they beheld Mr. Gabriel, fully dressed and groomed at his desk. “Bring him here,” he said in a velvet voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Gabriel was an imposing man, even sitting down. Had it not been for the luxuriousness of his suit and the immaculate way he combed his long, blonde locks of hair, his heavy features and menacing gaze might have gotten him mistaken for an enforcer. He grew no facial hair with which to hide his thin lips which always seemed curled into a grimace and his eyes, pale grey in colour, eternally peaked out from the shadows beneath his large brow. In certain lights, he seemed hardly human, and when standing at his full height of six foot seven, nearly three hundred pounds in weight, he could only be described as monstrous. His voice alone, and then only when isolated from the rest of him, had any potential for humanity, it being smooth and slightly high-pitched, even beautiful at times. When attached to the rest of him, however, it had a jarring effect, which merely completed the picture of intimidation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim and Donny stood on either side of Jack, each holding one of his arms, as they brought him forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My, my, what happened to you, dear boy?” Mr. Gabriel asked his small eyes burning with curiosity from beneath the pools of shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack seemed to go limp for a second. His face suddenly wore a baffling expression of elation. “Ah,” he breathed, “ah, you have seen the treasure! You know Him!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim saw Mr. Gabriel’s thin lips part only slightly and he thought, with incredulity, that the man was smiling softly to himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Would one of you like to explain what has happened to our dear friend?” Mr. Gabriel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, like I said,” Slim began, “I found him like this on the outskirts of town. I think he was trying to leave, maybe, I’m not really sure. He’s not been making much sense.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As though agreeing with him, Jack went on. “You hear Him, don’t you? Toiling away beneath the streets? Drawing up the fortunes from below?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s making perfect sense to me,” Mr. Gabriel chuckled. It was an almost girlish sound. Slim noticed then the slightest gesture as Mr. Gabriel began to gently stroke the large signet ring on his little finger. Had the office not been so dark, Slim might have been able to see the symbol on that ring: a serpent intertwined between the spokes of a wheel. “What do you think, Donald?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donny sputtered. “I didn’t have nothing to do with this, sir, I swear!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, come, come now,” Mr. Gabriel replied. “You know that’s not entirely true, of course.” He began to rise up from his chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please!” Donny cried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Mr. Gabriel rose, the room seemed to shrink around him, in reaction to his impossible size. “Calm down,” he said softly. “I just want to get a closer look at our friend.” As he approached Jack he murmured softly, “Your eyes, Jack. Has anyone ever told you that you have marvellous eyes?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack, still smiling, gestured to Donny and said, “His blood his weak.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donny turned on him then, but Mr. Gabriel, effortlessly, separated the two, all while hushing them quietly. Having gently pushed Donny away, he set his large, thick hands on Jack’s shoulders – a gesture from him which, alone, would have stopped the heart of a weaker man, but seemed not to perturb Jack in the slightest. He said, almost whispering. “It will have to do, nevertheless.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the flash of an instant, Mr. Gabriel produced a small, ornate cudgel from his belt and, with the grace of a man half his size, struck the side of Donny’s head with a sickening crunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim flinched, and then kept very still. Jack, according to his seemingly new permanent state of serenity showed no reaction. Mr. Gabriel turned to Slim. “Sorry about that,” he said quietly. His tone was one of embarrassment, it seemed to Slim. He walked passed them then and poked his head through the door and said something to the servant just outside who then proceeded to follow him back in. He gestured to Donny’s sprawled body. “Don’t worry about him,” he said, “I’ll take care of it. Please bring our new friend, Jack, here to the guest room. He will be staying with us for a little bit. Make sure he gets himself all cleaned up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, sir,” the servant said, as serene as Jack whom he presently turned towards. “Come along,” he said and Jack, still complacent, followed the servant out, leaving Slim with Mr. Gabriel and the unconscious, possibly deceased Donny Carmichael.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve done good work today,” Mr. Gabriel said, placing his free hand now on Slim’s shoulder as he put the cudgel back in his pocket with the other. Slim felt his knees nearly buckle, but kept it together. “I’ve heard about your work. You impress me, and our friend, Jack, didn’t have much to say about you – that’s a good thing, incidentally, as you can see.” Slim remembered Jack saying that he had a strange heart and swallowed dryly. “I think I’ll consider giving you a little more responsibility in this business of ours. Would you like that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Very much, sir,” Slim managed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m happy to hear that,” Mr. Gabriel replied. He took his hand from his shoulder and stepped towards Donny. He looked down at his crumpled body without pity. “What happened here today? If anyone asks, that is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a second, Slim froze, but clear-minded as he always was, his thoughts quickly returned to him. He cleared his throat. “Jack attacked Donny once we got here,” he said. “Then we had to take care of him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Very good,” Mr. Gabriel said and then returned to his desk. “You may go. Expect to hear from me soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, sir,” Slim said and left the office without sparing a glance at Donny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, as early as usual, Slim returned to Mitch’s diner. He ordered his decaffeinated coffee as always, but this time Mitch joined him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, what happened?” He asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jack went crazy,” Slim answered, taking a sip of his coffee. “Killed Donny, if you can believe it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s what they’re saying,” Mitch nodded. “What happened to Jack?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What do you think?” Slim said into his mug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ah, figures,” Mitch said, shaking his head. “That poor kid never had much luck. Him and that pal of his, Dusty. You heard about what happened to him?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gruesome, eh? When I heard, I thought Jack might have done it, but now they’re saying he did it to himself. Can you believe that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a damn shame.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But that can’t be a coincidence, can it?” Mitch said. “The both of them? The same day?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Crazier things have happened in this place,” Slim replied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No kidding,” Mitch said. “This damned town. There’s something wrong with it. It just eats people up, doesn’t it?”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/jack-and-the-wheel-of-fortune&quot;&gt;Jack and The Wheel of Fortune&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by P. Robbins at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;P. Robbins Writing&lt;/a&gt; on March 14, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letters to Ewan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/Letters-to-Ewan" />
  <id>/Letters-to-Ewan</id>
  <published>2019-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2019-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>P. Robbins</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;1--june-28th&quot;&gt;1 – June 28th&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ewan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this letter finds you at home and in good health. Word has reached me about your recent stint in the hospital. You will say you’ve suffered worse, but still I worry. We’re not young like we once were. The only comfort I have is in knowing that you’re in good hands: Jamie is a fine, strong woman, and more importantly she has an excellent sense of humour. She’s always struck me as the kind to laugh off all the little tragedies of the world. Maybe I’m wrong about that. I hope you’re both still laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose it’s been a while since I’ve written you, and for that I am deeply sorry. John wrote me and tried to put the shame on me something fierce. He said I was isolating myself from my family. Imagine that! He’s never tried to understand how it is with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I shouldn’t be harsh. You taught me that. I find it funny sometimes, how much I’ve learned from my younger brother. You were always the smart one – out of all of us. Maybe I ought to be embarrassed, but I can’t find it in me, especially what with us all being grown men and women now. What’s left of us, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn! There I go! I didn’t want to write about sad things. John says I’m too sombre, too melancholy, and he might be right about that, but he says it’s on account of my isolation. Well – let’s forget about that for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sorry it took me so long to write. You know how time just gets away from you. &lt;s&gt;Mary was like that, always just letting the world pass by without her, never had a care, that girl. God I miss...&lt;/s&gt; That isn’t to say I haven’t been productive! Actually, as it happens, I’ve been busy with the house and my carving, and in my spare time I’ve been reading a lot more. I picked up this book on writing letters, ironically enough. Apparently, in the traditions of certain cultures, it’s customary to begin a letter by writing about the weather. That makes enough sense, I suppose. When you haven’t talked to a person in a while there’s always that shyness at the beginning – you talk about neutral things like the weather and inoffensive mutual acquaintances, until the old feelings start to come back and you’re jabbering away like you’d never been apart. It seems incredibly silly that this kind of pattern should exist even in the writing of letters, at least if you expect to get to the meaty stuff within a single letter, as I generally do. But you know I am a strong believer in tradition. So, though it’s late, I hope you’ll let me fill you in on the recent weather, up here in Diver, Ontario. I’m sure you’d like to hear how the old homestead is withstanding the elements, at any rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer has come to the valley in full force, and Grovesend is thankful for it, after the bitter winter and dreary spring we’ve had. I’ve had my work cut out for me, repairing the house. We had leaks all through April, and I’ve only just managed to get the roof fixed up. But now the sun is shining, even despite the massive, drifting summer clouds which cast cool shadows against the trees and the fields that never stay for long. It is not too hot yet, nor too dry. There is a moisture in the air which allows you to taste the life that seems to grow without restraint all around – the vivid mosses and the blooming fruit trees. I’ve tried my best to funnel a bit of that life by resurrecting ma’s old garden, and by God I think I may have the old lady’s green thumb after all! The roses have come in well, a deep blood red which seems to brighten that old brick wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been some rain, but nothing like we had in spring. There are sun showers, occasionally – beautiful and eerie. Rainbows leap from one end of the valley to the other. On days like that, the big clouds seem to be hurrying everything along, as though the rain disturbs their leisure, for on other days they hang lazily in the sky, sharply white and huge against that lovely blue vault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, as I write, is a bit of an outlier. It’s the first overcast day we’ve had in weeks, and perhaps that’s why I’ve sat down to write at last. There’s nothing to do outside, and inside…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we’ve gotten over the little shyness by now, haven’t we? I might as well come to the meat of this letter. I’m sure John has written to you about me, just as he has written to me about you. I don’t approve of that. He doesn’t really understand what he’s been told, and passing along what he thinks he knows is bound only to do more harm than good. I don’t want you to worry about me, whatever he’s told you. I’m guessing Old George wrote him (crossed out) that bastard – the worst male gossip you ever heard! (end cross out), but what does George know? I can only imagine what he must have said: “That Colin! What a mess, wasting away in his folks’ home, a man in his thirties! They say he won’t ever get his act together. They say he’s hearing voices again.” You can bet I have a pretty good idea on who “they” are as well –  those old cronies of his. Good Lord! Sometimes I think the men in our town are worse gossips than the women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you know how John is –weak to shame, always on the defensive. I wonder where he gets that from. Maybe it was a bad mix of Grandpa Asheworth’s sensitivity and pops’ stubbornness. That’s bound to happen, I suppose. I feel for him, that brother of ours. He’s so busy, he shouldn’t have to worry about me. I’m just fine. Like I said, I’ve been keeping busy, and business is picking up again. I’ve hardly spent any time at the house, other than to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess you’ll understand me when I say that it’s only outside of the house that I feel the sense of isolation John tries to project on me, but unlike John I’ve always enjoyed my space. I’ve fixed up the old sun room and turned it into my studio. Of course, Grandma still uses it as her reading room, but you know how she is – always so absorbed in her books. She doesn’t mind my presence, and I don’t mind hers one bit. While I carve my pieces, I can listen to the sound of her turning the pages. Rarely she’ll speak up and without provocation recite a line from a poem, or a scene from a novel in that high voice of her, turned hoarse, it seems to me, by the years and years of easy laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voices. It seems cruel to me to call them that – our family, reduced to “voices”; so called by George and his ilk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably don’t want to hear about all of this. My point is only that I am doing well, and the things which John worries about, the things that he, against my wishes, tries to worry you about, regarding me, are not worthy of concern – but you probably already figured that. We’re the same, you and I. You know I’m not mad. &lt;s&gt;Or maybe you worry I'm like Uncle Gawain?&lt;/s&gt; John, though I love him to death, has always been the odd one out. Maybe that’s why he’s so sensitive about this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I hate to ask anything of you, especially given your health, I feel I don’t have a choice. Please, if you can, write to John, if you haven’t already, and tell him I’m well. I’ve already done so, but I don’t think he’ll take my claims seriously. It’s hard to describe, but I’m concerned that he’ll try to do something about me. I feel as though his patience with me is slipping. Maybe it’s all in my head, he is my brother, after all, and I know he would never do anything to hurt me, on purpose anyway, but you know what Grandpa used to say about the blindness of the self-righteous (more and more often the blinder he himself got, Ha! Ha!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will say no more harm against our brother – only that I wish he’d stop worrying about me so. Hopefully you can help, though of course your health comes first. I hope to hear back from you as soon as you’re well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colin Skinner&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2--july-15th&quot;&gt;2 – July 15th&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ewan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled to hear back from you so soon. It seems you’re in better shape than I gave you credit for! You’re still young after all, in spirit if not in body (Ha! Ha!). I do hope you’ll continue to take care of yourself – goodness knows Jamie can’t do it by herself (or maybe she can?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well – let me come right out and address the big concern from your letter: It boils down to a bit of a misunderstanding, but all is well now. I was not aware that George knew about my little project, nor that he had informed John. To answer your first question: No, Uncle Gawain did not come back. I haven’t heard him in years at this point, and you can be sure that I have not, and will not, do anything to beckon his spirit. As for your second question, no better, no worse. Take it as you will, but things are the same as they ever are here. As for that project of mine, I will disclose the full details presently, if only to spare you any concern. Perhaps you will even be able to find a way to make it palatable to our brother, though I doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was Mary, you see, it was her spirit I was trying to beckon – not Uncle Gawain’s. You should understand as well as anyone just how much I miss her – she was the best of all of us! You’ve said it yourself, and no one would ever contradict it. She inherited every Asheworth treasure, and not a few belonging to the Skinner family tree. She had Grandpa’s gift of the gab, and Grandma’s easy laugh, Ma’s sense of wonder, and Pops’ deep, abiding self-certainty. But that’s just it, isn’t it? She had too many treasures. She was never meant for this world. Those qualities she possessed which drew everyone to her were the threads of light which yanked her so quickly heavenward. Fair enough, let her sing with the angels, I say, and yet, knowing her, she must miss her family, no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wrote to her, just as I’m writing to you, and I burned the letters, just as I had with Uncle Gawain’s those years ago. When she didn’t answer, Grandpa suggested I go out to the edge of the property and carve signs into the trees, beckoning her, welcoming her. I set up lanterns until Grovesend was alive with light, and the whole family gathered out and called to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end she never came – still hasn’t. We tried a couple more times. You know how the family is, always optimistic. It’s what allowed us to take in Uncle Gawain that one time, back when he was alive. Do you remember? You must have only been nine or ten. I was sixteen, I guess. We gave him the attic and he stayed with us three weeks until the night he made a terrible racket and nearly burned the house down. I wonder, what kind of spirit was he trying to summon? He never did tell me, even when I called him back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Uncle Gawain could find his way home, why can’t Mary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But enough of that. To conclude, one of the neighbours, Joseph I’m guessing, must have heard me hollering, or otherwise caught a glimpse of what I was up to, and alerted George who passed it on to John. It seems a man can’t get any privacy anymore! And now you have the truth, do with it what you will. I only hope it’s eased your concern a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours with brotherly love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3--july-29th&quot;&gt;3 – July 29th&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ewan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another hasty reply! It’s been a while since we’ve kept a correspondence like this. Hopefully my pointing it out won’t jinx it, though I suppose that’s really up to us. You remember how serious pops was about jinxes. Though I love the old man dearly, I could never really buy into that. I’ve always preferred the calling out of fate, daring it to intervene and make a mess of plans. That always gets him going, me saying things like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say, I was a little surprised by your reply. I’m happy you took my confession, such as it was, so well, but if you’re getting homesick you know you can always make the trip up north. We’d all be happy to have you. Of course, I’m also happy to fill you in on the goings on here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first! I forgot last time, probably due to the seriousness of the subject, to open with a comment on the weather. Well – summer progresses well in Diver. It’s still as humid as ever, though of late it’s become a little overbearing. My poor roses have begun to wilt some – perhaps I didn’t give Ma as much credit as she deserved. There have been storms recently, powerful, earth-shaking ones. I watched, the other day, a lightning storm roll through the valley, and listened to the booming thunder echo through the woods. It was like that for a while before the rain finally began to fall, and fall it did! The water came down with one massive splash, soaking everything in a split moment. I was outside at the time, chatting with Ma, and I immediately ran for the house. Ma stayed outside though and danced in the rain. I could hear the sound of her footsteps as she traced the treeline, splashing around in the rainwater, her high laughter in the wet and electric air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there it is: same old Ma, her same old highs and lows. The highs come more often now than they did when she was alive. On the good days she’ll wander around, admiring the plant and animal life. Sometimes she’ll surprise me when I’m out working on the property, she’ll speak up and point out a monarch butterfly that’s stopped to say hello, or a blue jay that has decided to take a moment to admire my work. Once, the other day, when I was looking for something in the shed, she showed me a family of bats hanging by their clawed feet, asleep in the shadows. She’s a great reminder of life, even in her death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that when she’s out, wandering around, pops keeps an eye on her. I can’t see him, but I can hear his slow and steady footsteps in the creaking of the floorboards in the house. Ever the strong and silent protector, his presence is comforting. The only words he ever speaks are words of advice, it seems, occasionally he’ll relate one of his rare factoids – you remember them, don’t you? Do you remember the way he always sought hidden knowledge. He loved a good secret, but he also loved to share them with those he loved. Filled to overflowing with superstition, I think he always believed that the secrets he had and shared with us would be the salvation of him and our family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, however, Pops tends to say even less than Grandma, who as I mentioned last time, still spends her days reading in the sun room (we’ve gotten closer, sharing that space, and she’s started to tell me stories about grandpa when he was younger, but we’ll get to those…). The only exception in Pops’ reticence is when Ma is having one of her low days – yes, they still come, even now. On those days I can hear him in their room, speaking to her in that soothing voice of his. I can picture him there, at their bedside, her hand cupped in his as he whispers to her, reminding her of all the light and beauty in the world, promising her again and again that he will keep her and her children safe. Did you know that was what often got her so down? The thought that something bad might happen to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well – he takes care of her, as he always did. On those days I try to give them some space, and if I’m not working in the sun room with Grandma, I’m out on the porch with Grandpa. I like to sit out on the steps there and feel the sun on my face while I listen to the sound of his rocking chair. On some days, I think I can smell the smoke from his pipe – the one he carved, you remember. He spends his days, rocking and smoking, and when I join him we always get to talking. What about? I can hear you asking, but you know how it is with him. You can spend the whole afternoon jabbering away with the old man, or otherwise just listening to him flap his gums (the guy’s fondness for speech reminds me, in a way, of a drunk’s fondness for booze – he can never seem to get enough of it. Thank god he’s such a good speaker, but then again, if he wasn’t, I’m sure somebody would have figured out someway to shut him up), at the end of it all you’ll come away feeling warm and strangely enlightened, like you’ve been given some gift that will light up the rest of your week, but when you try to remember what topics had been touched upon you come up blank. So it is, generally, though I can say that a recent topic of conversation which came up was brief time in the Navy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You didn’t know our dear old maternal grandfather was a sailor once, did you? Grandma told me about it. He was only there for about five years, but in those five years he saw a lot of the world – from South-East Asia to the Caribbean! He told me some stories, the characters he met, the adventures he had; It came to an end when he started to show signs of our condition. It was not a happy ending, I’m afraid. You can imagine how it was, for him. He never really knew his mother, whom he inherited it from, and so he didn’t really understand what was happening. He thought he was going mad, as anyone in his position might. He ended up injuring his eyes – on purpose, mind you – and he was discharged. That injury, he told me, is why he started to go blind later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m thinking about it, it occurs to me that that is something he and I talk about quite a lot – this condition which he and I (and, to a lesser extent, thank goodness, you) have. What he sees, I hear, and you smell, occasionally, in Uncle Gawain it became something else altogether. I wonder how it manifested in Grandpa’s mother – perhaps she could feel them? I can only imagine how awful that must be, considering some of the one’s I’ve heard. To hear them can be bad enough, to see them, well, I can imagine why grandpa did what he did to himself when he was younger, but to feel them would be….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well – Grandpa learned to manage, and I believe I am making the most of my lot in life, though I know John would disagree. He’s never believed, but even if he did, I think he would still disapprove of my life. He would tell me that I need to let them go, this family of ours – but how can I? &lt;s&gt;It’s easier for him&lt;/s&gt; It’s hard when, for me, they never left. Everyone’s still right here, with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, if you’re feeling up to it, you should come for a visit. Maybe you’ll be able to smell Grandpa’s tobacco as he sits and puffs, rocking away the hours of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours as always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colin Skinner&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4--august-13th&quot;&gt;4 – August 13th&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ewan (and Jamie),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received Jamie’s letter. I was beginning to worry for a bit there, and now my worries are confirmed. I apologize for casting this jinx on us – that’s the last time I challenge fate like that. You’ll think I’m making a joke, but I do feel strangely responsible – as though my letter, the things I wrote to you last time, are somehow responsible for your current return to the hospital. I’ve noticed that I have that effect sometimes. It’s like, something will get me started and this box just opens, releasing all kinds of stuff, terrible things, things that I can’t rightly get a hold of to put them back. It’s hard to describe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weather: Summer has grown full ripe. The valley is a tangle of heat and light and life. The sound of life is cacophonous now, but rising over the chirps of the crickets and the songbirds, and the hooting of the owls and the high pitch clicking of the bats at night, is the melancholy song of the cicada, marking the beginning of the end of another summer. &lt;s&gt;You know how I get around this time of year…&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of you, brother, I hope you are not in pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wishing you well,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brother Colin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;s&gt;P.S. I may try again for Mary&lt;/s&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Jamie, if you’re reading this, please stay strong for my brother. He’s always been like our mother – he knows it and I know it – the lows can be bad, but you know better than us all how great the highs can be. The good days will always come again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5--august-27th&quot;&gt;5 – August 27th&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ewan (Or Jamie?),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been some time, and I have not received a reply to my previous letter. I am anxious about my brother’s health. John wrote me, but mentioned nothing more than I already knew. The rest was outside of my concern. I am trying to be patient with him, Ewan, but he grieves me so! It doesn’t help, this time of year. Summer is coming to a close and there is a chill on the wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In happier news, Mary has finally arrived! Though I don’t know how long she’ll stay for. You know how she is. That girl could never sit still. I had to write to her again, and once again the whole family came together to try and welcome her. I’m quite sure I gave Joseph a terrible fright, and I’m equally sure there will be hell to pay from John in time for it, but it was worth it, Ewan! It was so worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard Mary sing again! For the first time in so many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are well, you really ought to come for a visit. If Mary sticks around that long, you may just get to smell that perfume she always used to wear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiously yours,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6--september-14th-unsent&quot;&gt;6 – September 14th unsent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ewan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still no word? I don’t know what to do. I’m afraid, Ewan, for you and for myself. The summer is over and the sound of death in the valley is deafening. I can’t hear myself think! This has always been the worst time of year for me, but this year is especially bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leaves are turning colour, and with every one which curls up and falls from the branch, my head becomes closer and closer to being torn in two. The family is silent. They can do nothing to ease my pain. I feel alone now as John must thing I do all year round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shouldn’t be writing these things to you. God only knows the state you could be in. I wish I was there with you, little brother, away from this valley of death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary has left. She didn’t stay for long, and though I understand how it must be with her, I can’t help but be heartbroken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John wrote to me again. He told me not to write you&lt;s&gt;, the bastard!&lt;/s&gt; He wouldn’t tell me how you are, though. How can he criticize my alleged self-isolation, and then in the same breath try to isolate me from my own living brother? You have to help me, Ewan. Our patience for each other seems to be running out. I think George has written him again saying I’ve gotten worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have gotten worse – or rather, well, the summer has ended once again, and I am alone once again; Alone and yet stifled by this crowd of death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God, Ewan, it is worse than silence! I try to carve, but my hand shakes with exhaustion. I can’t sleep. Even writing this letter, I am uncertain if you’ll even be able to read my handwriting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What am I even saying? I can’t send this letter to you. John is right about that at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, around this time, I nearly drowned myself. I never told anyone. I went to the river and submerged my head, trying to block out the sounds. I spent longer and longer under the water until I found myself dreading coming up for air. I decided, in a split moment, to gulp the water into my lungs and let myself be carried away by the current, but I panicked. I managed to claw my way up the bank and vomit the water back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I will do to my ears what Grandpa did to his eyes, all those years ago, only I have heard about such injuries. I worry I would induce in myself a permanent state of vertigo. Can you imagine it? Spinning around in silence for the rest of your life? Is there no escape?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncle Gawain embraced it. I understand that now. This condition of ours – he took the good and the bad. “One foot in the grave,” Grandpa called it. Did I ever tell you? I used to speak with him, up in the attic when he was staying with us. Late at night I would sneak up there and we would sit across from each other in the candlelight. He would tell me secrets there – and not like the ones dad used to tell. These were real secrets, knowledge that was hidden for a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He would speak of the fumes of the spirit, the heat of decay. He would describe to me the smokey pits which are home to the ancient dead. Once, he held my hand over the fire and stared into my eyes as I tried to squirm away. The day after that, he tried to set himself ablaze – failed, nearly took us all with him. That was the end of our relation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I call him back? Back then I could hardly hear them. Was it this desire for secret knowledge, this inheritance from Pops, that compelled me so? (Or perhaps I inherited it from the Asheworth line, rather than the Skinner – Gawain himself is evidence for that). When he came to me, he unplugged my ears. I wish I could go back. I wish I could shut my ears to the sound of all the dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I’m not mad, Ewan, I know it, but when it gets like this I wonder if it wouldn’t be better. I have heard things. I’ve heard that they can zap the madness out of a lunatic’s brain with electricity. Do you think that would work on me? A few shocks between the ears to shut out the noise? Then again, I would miss the family. It’s hard to remember the good parts when it gets like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, who am I kidding? What is it I really want? To cure this world of death? Gawain once told me this world was made by death – a garden grown to be reaped by that legendary reaper himself. Maybe he’s right. When the valley was full of life, only a few weeks ago, it was nowhere near this loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsigned&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7--september-27th-unsent&quot;&gt;7 – September 27th Unsent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ewan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Mary, and now you. My heart cannot take it, and yet, I am too tired even for grief. I haven’t slept in days. The sound of the valley beats endlessly upon the walls, the doors, the windows. The world around me quakes. How can a world hold so much death?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when this house was full of the sounds of life, when we were boys. You and I and John and Mary. Grandma’s laughter and Grandpa’s stories, Ma humming to herself in the garden and Pops pacing the halls, watching over us all. John and I would play in the woods while you and Mary stayed in. Mary would sing and you would sit and dream. You were always so frail, little brother, but then again, perhaps we all were, in a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did everyone go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I might burn this letter, send it to you directly, but now I wonder if there’s a point. I can’t hear the ones I love over ceaseless blast of cold, uncaring death which fills the valley. The fruit has fallen and burst, the swarm of wasps have emerged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ll visit you instead, but I think I lack even the energy for that. John will be here soon anyway. He told me of your passing – a brief message. That’s how I know he’s on his way. He wishes to say the rest in person, I guess, but it’ll just be a waste. He’ll probably take me away from this place. I know I should resist him, but I’m just too tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have nothing more to say. I’m sorry I couldn’t see you one more time before you left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brother,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8--december-3rd-partially-burnt-recovered-by-dr-richter-psych-ward-st-lukes-hospital&quot;&gt;8 – December 3rd (Partially burnt, recovered by Dr. Richter, Psych Ward, St. Luke’s Hospital)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ewan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep this short. It’s quiet now, though I almost miss the noise. John finally went and did it, he got me committed – his own brother. He thinks I’m like Uncle Gawain, but all I can say is that this place explains why Gawain was the way he was. The things I hear in these halls – there is evil in this place. I need to get out of here, I need to go back home. I don’t know what John will do with the place. For the time being, however, I just need to hear a familiar voice. Please, come to me, Ewan, I’m begging… –&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fragment burned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–… can’t bare to be alone with the voices in this place. Now I understand what Gawain was talking about when he spoke about the smokey pits. There is sulphur on their breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to get my hands on some matches so I can get this letter to you, but I have a feeling they will try and stop me. I pray I will succeed. If I can’t get this letter to you, I don’t know what I’ll do with myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to hear your voice soon, Ewan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours forever,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colin&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Letters-to-Ewan&quot;&gt;Letters to Ewan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by P. Robbins at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;P. Robbins Writing&lt;/a&gt; on January 26, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tragedy of Jude, the Devil-Child]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/The-Tragedy-of-Jude-the-Devil-Child" />
  <id>/The-Tragedy-of-Jude-the-Devil-Child</id>
  <published>2019-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2019-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>P. Robbins</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The harvest moon seemed fit to burst and spill its strange, cosmic light upon the valley, the autumnal colours of which had been drained away. It was late at night, and yet Lydia, a sharecroppers daughter, stood outside in the cold and gazed up the western hill where could be made out the silhouette of a hunched figure outlined against an impossibly bright sky. She was calling to it, and it turned to face her then. She could see its eyes – the goat eyes of Jude, the Devil-Child, from the itinerant carnival which had arrived only the day before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had watched them set up the tents late in the afternoon, watched the young runaways put together the rudimentary rides and erect the food and game stands. Even from afar she had been able to hear the sound of their hammers drive the stakes – which held the moon-and-star covered tents in place against the warm afternoon breeze – into the ground. She had her mother’s curiosity, and the yearly carnival always snatched her attention, to her father’s occasional displeasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia’s father, the old farmer, was a wary sort, suspicious of the sun itself. He put little stock in anything besides his own hard work. How he had ever got Lydia’s mother to marry him was a mystery and was perhaps evidence of a shard of fear in her, for though she was a bit of a dreamer, and one who saw endless possibility in the world, she had also seen how such an attitude had the potential to destroy lives. Too many of her relatives, and her own father included among them, had met their ends impoverished, endlessly waiting for their life to begin, for the great wonders of the universe to blossom in their own small world. So she retreated, and possibly found a bit of comfort in a man who was so unlike her father that she would never have to fear a similar fate for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, Lydia’s father was far from impoverished, though that isn’t to say he and his own had it easy. Especially what with the poor harvests they’d had the previous years. This year, after a hopelessly dry summer, was looking to be the worst harvest yet. Thus, perhaps, Lydia’s father’s suspicions of the sun. He wasn’t alone, either, all the growers of the valley felt a nervous apprehension for the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One might think that such strife, large or small as it was, would extend to the carnival and her odd and colourful people, but, on the contrary such a poor season, always seemed to bode well for the carnies and their kin. It was not in spite of the troubles, but more likely directly because of them that the carnival, without fail, could expect a good turnout. People, trying to escape their woes, would go and gorge themselves on candy floss and peanuts and other junk food, take a spin on those primitive and, frankly, dangerous rides, and perhaps gawk a while in the sideshow tent at the various freaks and entertainers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that is where young Lydia had first laid eyes on Jude, who was called “The Devil-Child”, and his dreadful deformity. She had a keen sense of wonder, that girl, and though she had had to contend with an admittedly also strong sense of compassion in her decision of whether or not to visit the “Freak show”, she could not resist the temptation to see a spectacle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year around harvest time the carnival came to the valley, and every year she had convinced her parents to take her. Her father despised the festivities and looked upon the carnies with a healthy distrust, but harboured a guilty pleasure in the shooting games and, being something of a sharpshooter, always came away with many prizes. Her mother had a natural fascination with everything about the carnival, but what drew her more was the feeling of duty in her to make sure that the sense of wonder she detected in her daughter was well tended to. Perhaps this came from a place of regret for the way her own life had played out. Regardless, both she and her husband could tell well enough that their daughter was a bright and lovely child, and there was an unspoken understanding, which Lydia was a part of, that she would be successful no matter what. Point and case, Lydia was to go away the next year to attend school and further her education with the goal of becoming a teacher someday. This path filled her parents with pride, and it is very likely that her mother in particular, knowing that they would inevitably be left behind, wanted to make sure that that small part of her, that spark of curiosity and wonder at the world which dwelt in Lydia’s breast, would live on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure, Lydia’s mother did all she could to steer her daughter down a path which would lead her to a life of beauty and wonder. She was a covert consumer of poetry, and in secret she would lend an appreciative Lydia some of her most precious volumes. This was in an effort to give her a glimpse into the sublime, which had, for a time in her own youth, been the be all and end all of her existence before the fear instilled by the death of her father had set in. It was through their furtive forays into poetry that she discovered Lydia’s fascination with fables and fairy tales, an interest which she herself did not share (and, in truth, felt a touch of distrust towards) but nevertheless encouraged, seeing the way it lit up the wonder in her eyes. The carnival, in the end, was just one of many ways in which Lydia’s mother continuously tried to reveal to her a more fantastical and mystifying world beyond the farm she had lived on all her life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it was that when the carnival came around once more, after that dry and bitter summer, Lydia, now a responsible young lady was allowed to go with her friends and without parent supervision. Lydia’s father, unlike others who enjoyed the carnival as an escape from their worries, rather seemed to enjoy his current anxiety and would not be persuaded to go, even for all the sharpshooting prizes in the world, and Lydia’s mother, despite her own interest in going, thought it might be a good experience for her daughter who was about to venture into the wide open world, to get some life experience away from her parents’ watchful eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia went with three girls from school. To call them her friends would be a bit of a stretch. Truth be told, Lydia didn’t really have any friends. Perhaps her peers could sense something different about her. She was certainly the most intelligent for her years, and she knew it well enough. The other girls were fond of her, to be sure, but they couldn’t help but feel a distance between her and them that was neither positive nor negative, but simply was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They went out in the late afternoon after an early supper while the sun was low in the sky and the dirt path they took was bathed in a warm, orange light that deepened the colours which had started to stain the leaves in the trees. They had departed from another girl’s house and were taking the main road. Slowly as they went, the sound of music began to grow on their ears, carried by the brisk wind that promised a harsh winter to take the place of dying summer. Then came the smells: the fried food and the treats, intermingled with horse manure and mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls giggled as they came to the carnival and Lydia in particular, feeling no need to hide her joy, impressed her companions with her enthusiasm for the spectacles. To them, the carnival was just something to do, a way to kill time, a novelty at best, but to Lydia it seemed to promise something more. She looked upon the carnival as an intellectual, and rather than simply accept its strangeness as entertainment tried to dissect it and understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They started the night with junk food – this was a mistake, and Lydia, knowing that, refused to overindulge. The others, however, subconsciously feeling the thrill of the liminal space that was the carnival, stuffed their stomachs with candy floss and corndogs, not caring how they looked, and wrongly judged Lydia as just being too self-conscious. The consequence of their mistake came later, as Lydia predicted, after a period of playing games at various stalls when they decided to go on the rides, starting with the ubiquitous tea cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia had a lovely time, spinning around and around under the steadily darkening sky, while the other girls only just managed to survive. One girl, the tenderest of the bunch, needed to have a rest afterwards to keep from getting sick and the others were happy to join her. Lydia, on the other hand, not one to suffer fools (though neither one to say “I told you so”) politely excused herself to go on another ride while they recovered. Embarrassed, the girls said they would stay where they were and wait for her before joining her on the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe the ferris wheel,” the poor, tender girl, who now looked distinctly green, tentatively suggested, and the others sombrely nodded in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Lydia went on the swings for a while, but when she returned the girls were gone. For a moment she felt a rush of panic – not at the thought of being abandoned by her “friends” but more so at the thought of the trouble she would be in if her father found out she had been left alone at the carnival. This panic, however, quickly shifted into a kind of mischievous thrill. She was alone, yes, and the feeling of freedom, of being able to explore and do whatever she wanted was one she had never known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hesitantly, she began to walk around. The carnival was busy enough, almost to the point of being crowded, and yet she felt a great sense of space around her. She freely ducked in and out of crowds and with no particular direction in mind began to walk and explore. With her attention freed from any necessity for socialization, she found her eyes wandering. It seemed to her she could see clearer than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She observed, for example, the faces of the carnies, young and old, the mischief in their eyes. She could hear them speaking to one another, their strange and indecipherable cant, a language as foreign to her as Chinese and yet one which had, it seemed to her, the flavour of her own tongue. She observed the people too, most of them her townsfolk, some of whom she vaguely recognized. She saw the different way they looked around them, the varieties in their apparent interpretation of the festivities. There were those, like her mother, who seemed to take it in with a kind of restrained fascination, and others like her father, who looked, for the most part, disgusted at the display. What drew them? She wondered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By far, the most interesting expressions Lydia saw were those worn by the people emerging from one of the sideshow tents – namely, the one containing the freakshow. Here, the same kind of reactions to everything else seemed magnified. The people who left the tent were flushed, some thoroughly revolted by the sights they had seen, others strangely enthralled. Lydia, feeling her curiosity  being piqued, approached for a closer look, and stopped to read the bill:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Griselda, the Bearded Lady&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Lee Twins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Claire, the Human Pretzel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pip, the Shark-boy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knut “The Maw” Knutson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and, Presenting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jude, the Devil-Child&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The names of the various acts, such as they were, only hinted at what lay behind the curtain, and some more than others. Lydia had of course heard of bearded ladies, and even if she hadn’t, it was easy enough to imagine. Names like “the Maw” or the seemingly benign “Lee Twins” left almost everything to the imagination, and she could only begin to wonder. The rest of them at least called up some kind of visual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She stood there, trying to visualize the show inside the tent, trying to imagine what could give the people emerging such a look as she repeatedly saw on them, until she was suddenly hit with the realization that she could simply enter. The admission fee was a little steep, but well within her budget for the night (especially considering she hadn’t blown it all on junk food, like the others). Then she began to consider the reality of the place – they were people in there. Once she had heard her mother mention how cruel it seemed, to stare at, or worse, mock the freaks who, despite their deformities, were human nonetheless (one had to assume, anyway). Her father wanted nothing to do with them, though that certainly didn’t come from a place of compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, she made her decision. She could not have articulated her justification, but what it came down to was an agreement with herself that she would look upon the pitiable creatures not for entertainment but purely to satisfy and intellectual curiosity. To this end, she would try to treat the people with as much dignity as she could, refusing to laugh or gawk at them, but to keep a professional air of observation at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She could not have known that most of the acts actually, in one way or another, appreciated the attention they received, and derived their own satisfaction out of shocking their observers. In any case, Lydia was mostly successful. The bearded lady seemed nice, she thought, and the Lee Twins (Siamese twins, unsurprisingly), though a little strange to be sure, when looked at at the right angle could have been two shirtless young brothers simply sharing a bench. The acts got more grotesque as she continued, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claire, at first glance, was the most normal of the bunch, but her talent proved disturbing. She was a contortionist to the extreme, capable of bending her joints beyond what Lydia would have thought possible. The worst part was the sound: the popping and the snapping of joints and ligaments, and all the while Claire (who truly enjoyed frightening her “guests” as she called the spectators) wore a horrified mask of agony. Lydia hurried on to the next act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pip, the Shark-boy, was an odd one. He was hardly a boy, and was indeed bigger than most of the men at the carnival. He was a Pacific Islander, and his body was covered in intricate tattoos which Lydia secretly thought were splendid. His teeth had been filed down into razor sharp points, like shark teeth, but what really completed the picture were his webbed hands and feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up was the mysterious Maw, and much like Claire, Knut seemed rather normal at first glance, again, up until he began his act. Knut Knutson could, supposedly, eat anything, and he tried to prove this night after night by consuming the most inedible of foods, from rancid meet, to broken glass, and finally metal nails and screws. At this point, Lydia had some trouble maintaining her composure, for she was well and truly disgusted by Knut Knutson’s act, and the way he looked lustily upon the female spectators, deriving, unbeknownst to anybody, sexual pleasure from the looks of disgust they gave him, did nothing to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Lydia came to what she had heard people referring to as “really, the main act of the whole show”: The Devil-Child himself. Perhaps it was the fact that she had already had a hard time with Knut Knutson, or perhaps the Devil-Child really was just as horrible as all that, but the moment she saw him she dropped all her airs entirely. Despite herself, her face contorted into an expression of pure horror and disgust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Pip, who was no boy by any stretch of the imagination, Jude really did seem something of a child. The smallness of his size was compounded by the way he hunched himself, and behind the terrible deformities of his face could be seen a young complexion. Just so, it was as easy to see where the name “Devil” came from, for his body was covered in fine black fur, his hands and feet were clawed, and his face, while distinctly human, seemed permanently fixed into an impish glare. From his forehead, a little off-centre, protruded a hideous, twisted horn, and when his hairy lips were parted one could see a set of teeth which rivalled even the shark-boy’s. But there was something worse about him yet, something which Lydia could not exactly put her finger on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She would work it out in a little while. For the moment, she didn’t really have a chance to take it in, for as soon as she saw the Devil-child for herself she stifled a scream and fled the tent, running into the cool night and through the still flushed crowd outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took Lydia a while to compose herself once more and the calmer she became, the guiltier she felt, by her actions as much as her thoughts. At first she was horrified by her reaction and this horror was amplified by her initial impression that the Devil-Child was indeed just a child. Poor boy! She lamented internally, to be so hateful! Then she got to wondering if what she saw was even really human, but this only made her rebuke herself. Of course it was human! She told herself. Didn’t you see the way it stared and blinked?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it was. That was the worst part: the eyes. The child had had the eyes of a goat, with strange elongated pupils, simultaneously unfeeling and, yes, she realized: sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poor boy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time passed, she managed to steady herself, though the pang of guilt did not leave her. For a while she considered going back into the tent and apologizing to the unfortunate creature, but she didn’t have enough money for another ticket of admission, and in any case the other girls had reappeared. To Lydia’s surprise, they seemed almost as disturbed as she was, and the cause of this they revealed to be the fact that they had just sat down with a fortune teller who had said nothing but hurtful things to them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shes a witch,” one of the girls, the one who had been sick earlier, whispered fearfully. Her green complexion had turned now pallid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls explained that they had had to leave in order to find a privy, and when they came back they waited where they’d been but it was apparent that Lydia had come and gone and so went to look for her before getting distracted by the horrible fortune teller. Lydia, preoccupied as she was, did not think to ask even herself why they hadn’t left one of them behind to let her know this, but it didn’t matter. The girls themselves were so focused on their own dreadful encounter that they noticed nothing wrong with her, or if they did they assumed it was only a displeasure from the sting of having been ditched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls, disappointed overall with their experience, decided to call it a night then. As they went to leave one of them tugged at Lydia’s sleeve, pulling her out of her guilty, self-torturous thoughts, and pointed out the fortune teller who, presently, stood outside her tent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s her,” she said, “that’s the evil woman.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fortune teller was a dark gypsy woman, with long black hair that was braided and decorated with arcane ornaments. She was bare-footed, which was a baffling sight to behold, and her dress was covered with colourful patterns that no local woman, including the girls, would be bold enough to wear in public. She smiled at the girls, a devilish smile, and they hurried along. Lydia stayed back a bit, returning the stare from the Fortune Teller. They seemed to eye each other curiously for a moment, before Lydia turned and hurried to rejoin her group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home they described the awful things the gypsy had told them. They had asked questions typical of girls their age, mostly relating to their love lives and their dreams for the future. They were told, essentially, that none of them would marry the love of their life, that they would remain in town until the end of their days as pitiful farm wives, slaving away inside just like their mothers before them, that they would never see the world, and that their deaths would be a relief from all the toil in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Foul bitch,” one of the girls muttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once home, Lydia went straight to her room and collapsed into her bed. The talk of the gypsy fortune teller had managed to take her mind off of the Devil-Child, but slowly the topic came back to her, and before long she was writhing with guilt. “The poor boy, the poor boy,” she repeated to herself forlornly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually she tried to go to sleep, but it was no use. The image of the Devil-Child was seared into her mind and it scared her terribly, and every time she felt the wave of fear rise up it was met by an almost worse wave of guilt and unbearable compassion. How can someone live like that? She wondered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the while, tossing and turning, she drank from a cup of water on her night table. Eventually, around midnight, this had a natural effect on her, and unable to sleep anyways she rose to go to the privy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an awful thing on any night, to have to go out into the dark to use the privy, but on such a night as this, what with the state she was in, plus the chill in the air, it was unbearable, but the more she tried to resist the urge the more she felt the need, and so, putting on a brave face, she went outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially she felt a relief at how bright the night was. A few scattered clouds hurried along, illuminated by the shining moon and seemed even to spread its light out further. For a moment Lydia forgot her need and stopped to admire the beauty, but it quickly came back to her and she rushed to finish her business. It was on the way back inside, stopping again to admire the way the moonlight lit up the fields and the western hill that she saw the silhouette of the Devil-Child standing high on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breath was ripped from her chest in an instant, as though by a sharp cold wind. She stared wide-eyed. The guilt she had felt had slowly begun to fade, but now it evaporated entirely. What is he doing here? Did he follow me? What does he want from me? These questions flew through her mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then she heard the sound: The child, the creature, whatever it was, softly weeping. All the compassion flooded back into Lydia along with a hefty dosage of guilt at having suspected any ill motive on the part of the child. It occurred to her that it was not at all even aware of her presence, and suddenly she was filled with an urge to call out to it, though she didn’t know what to say. Then the answer came to her: What could give the creature more dignity than to call to it by name?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jude?” She called, quietly at first, as though uncertain she wanted to be heard, “Jude, is that you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creature turned to her, and there were the eyes, those goat eyes. Once again they horrified her, but this time she kept a hold of herself. “Jude, are you okay?” She asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crying stopped, and for a moment Lydia felt the cold of the air penetrate a little deeper than her skin. Then she heard its voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who are you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice was uncanny, for though the creature before her did not hardly seem human, its voice was entirely so. Its voice was that of a boy’s, and a young one at that. It sounded sweet and sorrowed, and it was enough to wring Lydia’s heart and urge her up the hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My name’s Lydia,” She replied, boldly. Its voice had rid her of any fear. She felt, with a certainty that would have concerned most, that this creature truly was just a poor boy as she had both feared and hoped. “You’re Jude, aren’t you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stay back,” the creature said, and there was fear on its voice now – a scared little boy. “Don’t look at me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I saw you earlier,” Lydia said, the guilt rising up in her throat, “I’m afraid my reaction was unkind. I wanted to apologize to you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Di you follow me?” Jude asked, confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia almost laughed. “This is my home,” she told him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry,” Jude quickly exclaimed, “I shouldn’t be here.” He spoke shakily. “I’ll leave, I promise. Esme will be expecting me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s alright, really,” Lydia protested, unsure of why it was she wanted this creature to stay. She had said her apology, as she wanted, but her heart went out to the pathetic being. She wanted know to reach out to it, to help it in a way. “Who’s Esme?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point she found herself nearly at the top of the hill. The creature was only a few yards away from her, and up close, in the clear moonlight, she could make it out well: There in the pale light were his clawed hands and feet – he wore no shoes, presumably due to the fact that there would be none that could fit them. His face, half obscured by the night and half by the hair that covered it was turned away from her, and the large protruding horn glistened in the eerie light. He watched her suspiciously with one large goat’s eye which, like his face, betrayed no hint of emotion. Only his voice seemed to give him away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Esme takes care of me,” he said and then in a quieter voice explained, “She’s a fortune teller.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image of that barefooted gypsy woman and her malicious grin flashed across Lydia’s mind, followed by the words of the other girls: “Evil woman.” “Foul bitch.” “She’s a witch.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As though reading her mind, the boy added, in a fearful tone: “She’s a witch.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I see,” Lydia replied, a little stunned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She used to be nice to me, but she’s changed,” Jude explained, and his words were tumbling out of him like water through a crack in a dam, the way children sometimes talk, so lacking in self-consciousness, and with a mixture of terror and relief, which presumably came from his ability to confess something he had kept secret for a long time, he declared: “I’m frightened of her!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small part of Lydia could see a glimmer of humour in this declaration – here was a truly monstrous creature declaring that he was frightened of his mother-figure. But Lydia, in all her compassion, took the creature’s confession very seriously, and gravely asked it, “Why are you afraid?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Esme used to be kind,” he explained, “she used to talk with me, listen to me, but she doesn’t listen anymore, and she talks strange. She used to look at me like she looked at other people, not the way other people look at me, and she would comfort me when I felt bad, but she doesn’t do that anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia thought of scandals she had read about parents abusing their children. She tried to make sense of this confession. “Does she hurt you?” She asked, helplessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” the boy admitted, lowering his head even further so that his words came out muffled, “But I think she wants to. That’s what I’m afraid of.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s awful!” Lydia cried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People used to hurt me,” Jude said, and his voice trembled. He shook with tiny sobs though Lydia noted that no tears fell from the unblinking eye with which he stared at her. “They would say mean things – they still do that – or they would just run away from me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m so sorry,” Lydia said, now feeling tears well up in her own eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re nice though,” the creature said, almost seemingly wanting to comfort her. “What’s your name?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m Lydia.” She extended her hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jude eyed her hand and shook his head slightly. “I’d better not,” he said, without any further explanation. “It’s nice to meet you, Lydia. You’re kind. You’re just like how Esme used to be. You don’t scream at me or say mean things.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is there anything I can do to help you?” Lydia asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes, when it gets to be too much, I leave and I wander the hills,” Jude said wistfully, ignoring Lydia’s question. “Esme used to get mad at me about that. She used to say I would get in trouble if someone found me, but you’re so nice, Lydia.” He giggled then. “Thanks for talking with me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took off then, back down the hill. It made Lydia jump, to see the boy get down on all fours and instantly break out into a sprint. She watched him descend the hill on the other side, down towards the Carnival which stood silent under the harvest moon, the tents rippling in the cold wind. She shivered then, feeling the cold for the first time since she had started talking with Jude. She realized her hands and her feet were numb and quickly hurried in the opposite direction, back towards her own house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day Lydia went through her chores in a haze. Her experience with Jude had bled into a short, restless sleep which had only come to her once the cold and her exhaustion had taken their tolls. As a result, she spent much of the morning dazed, trying to separate dream from reality. Looking back, she realized, though the boy had sounded very childlike his words were not so. There seemed a kind of intelligence to them that betrayed his apparent years. This fact, such as it was, rather than concerning her only made the creature more alluring. She wondered ceaselessly: Just who is this Devil-Child?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no school that day, but Lydia’s mother kept her busy while her father tended to the crops, poor as they were. Lydia felt detached all the while. Her body went through the motions while her mind remained atop the western hill conversing with the strange malformed child in the moonlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early afternoon, when there was a break in the work, Lydia found her feet taking her back to the hill. Later she would think that subconsciously her mind must have felt incapable of righting itself until she went back to the scene of the meeting. Reaching the top of the hill in the golden afternoon she took a quick glance around. There were no traces of the Devil-Child. Then she turned her attention back down the other side of the hill and towards the carnival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was quiet. There were only a few people milling about, tiny specks crawling amidst the large, colourful tents, and the megalithic structures of the rides. One figure, however, she made out, was walking towards her from the bottom of the long, shallow hill – a figure in a bright and colourful dress, with long black hair blowing in the light afternoon breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia froze. She was tempted to turn and run back towards her house, but the thought of her parents kept her in place, for if this woman, this “witch” apparently, were to speak to them, who knows what she would say? She remained where she was in a state of indecision until at last Esme was within shouting distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lydia?” The gypsy shouted. “Is that you, girl?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia said nothing. Esme continued to approach her, her voice quieting the closer she came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What did you see, last night, I wonder? Up here on this hill?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re Esme, I guess,” Lydia said, trying to sound big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esme did not respond to her statement. “I was just coming to warn you,” she said, “Don’t trust that devil. He is exactly how he seems, in his flesh I mean. He’s the devil’s own child. I mean that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How can you say such a thing?” Lydia exclaimed, genuinely outraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Poor little girl,” Esme replied, shaking her head. Her smile was cruel. “How does he sound to you? Like a helpless little boy? It’s a trick, can’t you see? He uses it to lure people in. I have heard his real voice – it would curdle your blood.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia felt a kind of hesitation. She wasn’t sure what to say, but Esme went on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s got his eyes on you now, girl. He won’t leave you alone, not until we move on together, which wont be for another week or so. Until then, I suggest you stay indoors at night. Don’t come out, no matter what he says to you, or how he sounds. He is exactly how he seems on the outside – just remember that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t believe you,” Lydia said after a little while, but there was no force behind her words. She didn’t know what to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something fell in Esme’s face then. The cruelty dropped from her mouth and she seemed to Lydia much older all of a sudden. “I can’t make you follow my advice,” she said, bitterly, “but I hope to God, for your sake, that you do.” She half turned away then, and said, “One day, I’m going to have to kill that creature, I think. I’m starting to realize that now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia was shocked by this statement, though not as much as she would have been before the conversation. Uncertain, she watched Esme descend the hill once more, slower now, just as she had watched the Devil-Child descend the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Lydia returned to the house, she felt faint. Her cheeks were flushed, and her legs were shaky. Her mother, perceiving something was wrong, sent her to bed and started to fix her some soup. “Maybe you caught a chill at the carnival last night,” she said, “It was a cold night, after all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In bed, Lydia could not find rest or ease. She tried to take her mind off of things by reading from one of her books. She pulled out a tattered old tome of fairy-tales that her mother had bought in secret at a secondhand book shop in the city. This one seemed nearly ancient, but it had lovely illustrations. She flipped through it idly, reading a passage here and there, until at last she stumbled upon a picture of a Satyr – half goat, half man. She stared at it a while and read the description - “A lustful spirit, dwells in the woods and other remote places. Lovers of wine and women. Great pursuers of sin.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia shut the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point after supper she must have fallen asleep, for time had jumped from a brilliant, gold and red evening to the cold dead of colourless night. She awoke from a terrible dream, slick with perspiration, gasping for breath. A roar echoed in her ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She blinked at the darkness around her, breathing heavily for a moment, before burying her face in her hands. She stayed that way for a while, her mind racing over confused thoughts and images. Then came the loud tap at the window. She jumped and nearly yelped with terror. She looked at her window. There was nothing there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another tap. She had seen it this time: a pebble had flown through the air and bounced off the window frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hesitatingly, she rose and peered out the window and to the yard below. There he stood: the Devil-Child, or his shape at least. Though the moon and the night were still bright, it wasn’t anywhere near as much as the night before. So it was that she could only make out the rough shape of the creature, but a distinctive shape it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed to see her in the window, for it through no more pebbles. Instead it raised a clawed hand and waved gently. The gesture was so sweet, so childlike, that for a moment Lydia forgot everything Esme had told her that afternoon. She felt the urge to rush downstairs and meet him outside. For the moment, she simply waved back. Then it motioned for her to come down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hesitation took over. She remembered Esme’s words, the weary look in her eyes when she said that one day she would have to kill the creature. She had said those words as though they were a great burden. Still, she did not entirely trust the gypsy woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She stepped away from the window and considered her options. The longer she considered them for, the more her compassion began to slip through. She thought about how the creature had said Esme had changed, how her kindness towards him had left. Then she thought of him standing out there in the cold, needing someone to talk to, craving the kindness that everyone else refused to show him, waiting for her to emerge. Tentatively she descended the stairs, trying not to wake her parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the kitchen, standing at the back door, she looked into the night and was only barely able to detect Jude in the obscurity. A large cloud had drifted in front of the moon, turning the land dark. She poked her head out into the cold air and called out softly: “Jude? Is that you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His voice, though quiet, seemed to be carried clear by the cold wind to her ears. “Lydia, thank your kindness! I need your help. Esme has gone crazy. I think she wants to kill me!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice was as childlike as ever, but she recalled what Esme had said about Jude’s “real voice”, and she shuddered at the recollection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What can I do?” Lydia asked, still trying to decide whether she should stay indoors or rush out to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” Jude said, and she could hear him crying, “Nobody will help me. They’re all afraid of me. Esme keeps saying terrible things about me, but they’re not true! She just doesn’t want anyone to help me. She said something about a sacrifice! I’m so scared of her, but I have nowhere to go, nowhere to run to. Please, Lydia, you’re the only one who can help.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia’s heart raced, and emotion surged upwards from her guts into her throat. She stepped outside and started towards the creature. “You poor boy,” she cried, “you poor, poor boy! Come to me!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still weeping, the creature rose and took a few steps towards her, its goat-eyes glowing in the darkness. What little moonlight shone through the massive cloud glinted on his sharp, razor-like teeth. “Oh thank you, Lydia, thank you!” He cried, so childlike it broke Lydia’s young heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gunshot which followed was nearly deafening. It sounded from directly behind her, and Lydia could feel the air shifted by the bullet as it whizzed by and found its mark in Jude’s chest. He fell, with a cry that paralyzed Lydia – a terrible scream, half child and half beast, full of agony and outraged shock, followed by animal like whimpering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jude!” Lydia cried and then turned back to face her father who stood at the doorway, his rifle still smoking. He looked pale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I saw it from the window,” he stammered. “That thing isn’t human. Get back inside, Lydia!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;disobeying her father, Lydia ran to the slumped body of the creature. Jude stared up at her with those terrible goat-eyes – she could see no pain in them, no sorrow, no fear. His pointed teeth were stained from the blood which bubbled behind them and dribbled down his cheeks from the hairy corners of his mouth, and from deep in his throat rose a forlorn, high pitched whistle. It sounded as though a child, somewhere inside of him was calling up to her: “Lydia, it hurts! Oh, Lydia it hurts! Please, help me, Lydia!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hot tears streamed down Lydia’s cheeks. “Oh, God,” she said, “Oh, God!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then she heard her father shout, not at her, “Stay back! Who are you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lydia looked. Esme, in her long bright dress, was coming down the western hill. The cloud had passed from in front of the moon, and in the new ray of light they could see that she had a knife in her hand. She stopped and stared at the scene, her eyes wide and crazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You killed him?” She asked. “You shot him and killed him?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stay back, I said!” Lydia’s father boomed, levelling his rifle at the gypsy woman. He stepped out from the door and moved to position himself between Lydia and Esme. Lydia’s mother appeared at the door frame with a look of horror. “Get Lydia inside,” Lydia’s father commanded her, and she ran to her daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come along, Lydia,” she urged her, but Lydia was inconsolable. She would not move for as long as the creature still wheezed its bloody breathes. Finally, her mother had to forcibly lift her up and drag her into the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut the door,” Lydia’s father said to them, and then turning his attention back at Esme shouted once more, “I won’t say it again, stay back!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Esme stopped. Her hand which clutched the knife fell limp at her side and she just kept repeating her initial statement: “You killed him. You killed him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the house Lydia sat and stared at nothing as her mother tried to comfort her while listening for her husband. It was difficult to make out what was said. There was an exchange of words, and then a scream, and finally another gunshot. After a few moments the door opened and Lydia’s father entered, his face pale and slick with sweat. It was as close as Lydia had ever seen her father lose composure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That woman was crazy,” he said, “I had to do it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first light there were police. Questions were asked, and honest answers were eventually given. In the end, Lydia’s family never saw any trouble, though the manager of the carnival did try to stir some up. Lydia never found out what happened to the body of Jude, the Devil-Child – more than likely he was incinerated. She had heard one of the police officers call him an “abomination to God” when he first saw the remains, and this had sent her into a hysterical fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shock of it all would stay with her for a long while, and the dreams would never really leave until the day she died. In those dreams of hers she saw his goat-eyes in the moonlight, full of sadness and betrayal.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/The-Tragedy-of-Jude-the-Devil-Child&quot;&gt;The Tragedy of Jude, the Devil-Child&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by P. Robbins at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;P. Robbins Writing&lt;/a&gt; on January 20, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What they found on Big River]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/what-they-found-on-Big-River" />
  <id>/what-they-found-on-Big-River</id>
  <published>2019-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2019-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>P. Robbins</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Joshua and Eli stared bleary-eyed at the body tangled in their fishing net. “This is a bad thing,” Eli simply muttered, and in his heart he thought that it foretold worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She’s just a girl,” Joshua whispered. His voice was choked and hoarse. He turned away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun shone high on Big River, and Laurie bobbed in near silence as the ripples in the water gently splashed against her hull. Neither man knew that the body in their net once belonged to a girl of the same name as their boat: Laurie, only twenty-one years of age; a tall blonde with a smile that could kill, reduced to this. She was naked and her skin had a greenish tinge. Bits of her had been chewed on by the watery denizens of Big River. Even so, Eli would have wagered that she hadn’t been there long. He didn’t like to look at her, the state she was in, and after a while he turned away too. Then he heard Joshua putting back on his rubber gloves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing?” Eli asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We can’t just leave her there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli wanted to argue with him, but he knew how it would sound should he suggest the alternative, so he just repeated his earlier statement: “This is a bad thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I believe that’s what they call an understatement,” Joshua said and grunted as he got his gloved hands under the girl’s arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally Eli would have joked back at him, but at the moment he felt as though a pair of cold hands had wrapped their icy fingers around his throat. His heart nearly stopped as Joshua began yanking the body from the net when, for just a moment, he thought she might fall apart in his arms. Luckily she was held together by the grace of rigor mortis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua managed to get the body free relatively easily enough. He tried to treat her gently and with dignity. Eli, meanwhile, felt a pang of guilt at not helping, but being deeply superstitious both by nature and by upbringing, he would not touch the body. He tried to justify it to himself as a job more fit for a captain than a first mate, but that only made his guilt worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the time being, Eli descended below deck to fetch a bottle of rum from their stash. By the time he emerged with it, Joshua had got the body wrapped up in a spare blanket they would have to throw away. Eli handed the bottle to his old friend, and it was taken without a word. In turn they each took a pull as they stared at the covered lump of one-time living flesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess we ought to take her down to the city,” Eli suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lord knows that’s where she came from,” Joshua agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, they moved without haste. The discovery of the poor girl filled the hot air with a kind of lethargy. Joshua sighed deeply as he took up the helm and Eli, who was always quiet and somewhat morose, seemed especially so as he went to his own post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two did not talk as they followed the river south towards the city. The trip was not long, in truth, though it felt so for the two fishermen. Occasionally they would glance at the covered body and shudder. Eli, much to his chagrin, could not dispel a certain feeling which had come over him – that something had changed, that the two old men had brought aboard something more than just a corpse. The superstition in him made him want to do something about it, like say a prayer over the body or some such act, but he could not think of what exactly was appropriate in such a case. His father, who had taught him all he knew, had never addressed just such a situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they reached the city and got their boat in the marina, Eli went to fetch the police, leaving Joshua with the remains of the girl. While Eli was gone, Joshua lit a cigarette and kept watch. His eyes never shifted from the misshapen blanket as he puffed away. It was as though he expected her to get up and walk off at any moment. At any rate, he was glad he had covered her up the way he had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Eli returned with the police they were kept busy enough to not think too hard about what it all meant. All that was required of them for a time was their detailed recollections. There were questions, answered consistently and with ease. When all was said, the body was taken away to be examined. Joshua, at one point, tried to ask his own questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who was she?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What was she doing out there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why did this happen?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lawmen answered none of them. They left, body in tow, and Joshua and Eli were alone once more on the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By then it was getting dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess we might as well stay here,” Joshua suggested, “call it a night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you want to go into town?” Eli asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua shrugged. “I don’t know what it is I want to do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli nodded. For a while the two were silent, and then Eli went and leaned on the railing of the deck. From his pocket he produced an heirloom watch and checked the time. “We’ve got to eat at least,” he said. “I remember when my old man died, how strange it was to think we needed to eat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How much of that rum have we got left?” Joshua asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the sun had fully set and taken all its light with it, the old timers were good and drunk. Joshua shook the bottle and listened to the splash of the finger or two of rum left in the bottle before setting it down between the two of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How long have we been doing this?” He asked, suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Five and thirty odd years,” Eli replied, his head bobbing drunkenly in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And we weren’t young when we started,” Joshua said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m feeling it, more and more,” Joshua admitted to him, “but what we saw today. That makes it worse, somehow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Life is brief, Josh, that you’ve got to know.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re right as always, old friend,” Joshua nodded. “It’s just funny. I kept thinking there would be more time. In her case, there was more time, or there should have been, at least. This world does not wait for anybody, it seems to me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That is doesn’t,” Eli agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is a funny thing, indeed,” Joshua murmured, “When I was young, I used to think I would do something great, become somebody important. Not that I’m complaining about this quiet life of ours. I’ve seen what greatness and importance takes from a man, and I would rather our simple labour. You helped me see that, Eli, and yet…” Joshua trailed off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yet?” Eli asked after a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” Joshua said and started to roll another cigarette. Eli could hear, in the pitch darkness, the sound of Joshua’s dry tongue scraping the paper as he sealed it closed. Then he flicked open his lighter. After a while the light disappeared and he exhaled deeply. “I guess I’m just tired,” he said after another long pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now don’t go talking like that, Josh,” Eli said sternly, sitting upright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t mean that,” Joshua explained. “I don’t mean where that poor girl has gone. I just mean…” He searched for a moment and then clarified, “The toil of it all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But that’s all there is,” Eli said, echoing the words of his father. “Life is just work, in the end.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But for it to end like that?” Joshua asked. “It just seems to me so pointless.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli didn’t know how to respond to that. Strangely, their conversation made him feel nostalgic. It reminded him of his early days with Joshua; back when they were just a couple of drifters in life, young and lost. To Joshua’s point, he had to wonder: Where had those years all gone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the old days, Joshua had been the quiet one – a dreamer, lost in his imaginings of what the future would bring, but forever reticent about his past. Well, “forever” wasn’t completely true. It did take Eli ages to get it out of the kid: Vagrant, parentless at the age of thirteen, street urchin, but one who managed to rise out of what most would call a hopeless situation. Despite having little to no formal education, Joshua was probably the most well-read person that Eli knew. It was long a source of endless amusement that, how someone in Joshua’s position could end up more book-smart than he was street-smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, it had made for good conversation back in the day, for though Eli could probably count the number of books he’d read in his entire life on his two hands (Even with his missing pinky finger on his left), he considered himself a man who knew his place in the world. His father, a sailor who lived by a code, not based on science or even religion, but rather a paradoxical mix of common sense and the less-than-sensical patterns of various seaworthy superstitions he had picked up over the course of his career, had taught him all he needed to know about how to live in the world. Mostly it came down to living simply – taking only what was needed and paying sweat for food and shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The only thing you can trust is your own two hands,” Eli’s father would say, “and even they can be deceitful bastards.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such was life, according to the old man, long dead. When his own hands failed him he must have found cause for trusting his son, at least, to take care of him. Eli had only been in his twenties at the time, fresh faced and eager to see the world as his old man had been at his age, and it was during those years his father had taught him most – specifically the more esoteric practices behind living off the water. It was this knowledge that he brought to Laurie and his captain, who he had once, in their younger days, taken under his wing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua had learned to settle down over the years, and with his vast capacity for knowledge, he had easily overtaken Eli – thus his current role between them. Eli’s own role evolved into one of a grounding sage – he was the rock which held the string of his longtime friend’s kite in place, keeping him on the right track. Together they had had a good, if somewhat simple life. Now, however, it seemed Joshua was beginning to let his thoughts run away from him once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Say we retired,” Joshua said, suddenly. “Say we didn’t have to work. We’ve got some money saved up. What would you do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sure I’d get bored, not having to work,” Eli answered, after giving it some thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua laughed aloud. It was his first laugh since they’d found the body. “Oh, come on now, Eli, don’t you ever wish for a break,” he asked, “That’s all I’m talking about: A break. Not having to work for a while. Not necessarily doing nothing, you know?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli picked at his beard and looked out over the oily lights of the city reflected in the water of the marina, and the hazy halo above. “What would you do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think I’d read more,” Joshua nodded to himself, “Try to learn something new, while my eyes and my brain are still capable. Maybe I’d even travel somewhere completely foreign.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli’s father, who had been all over the world, had told him that travel was a fools pursuit. On the surface, someplace else might seem different, might promise a different kind of life, “But spend enough time ashore and you’ll find it’s all the same gutter.” No matter what current you take, what river, what road, they all lead to the same bleak destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli decided to meet Joshua halfway, if only to help steer him away from doing something rash. “Maybe a vacation wouldn’t be so bad,” he admitted, halfheartedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now you’re talking,” Joshua said excitedly, heaving up the bottle once more and taking another swig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We could get the hell away from this city for a while,” Eli continued, and though he was just saying the words he thought his friend wanted to hear, they started to resonate with him in a way. Suddenly, he was thinking about his father’s old cabin up north – the fresh pines and the rocky cliffs, bright cold afternoons spent casting a line into a clear, misty stream, and starry nights by a fire, singing hymns or otherwise just listening to the crackle of the burning wood and the whistle of the northern wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua waved his hand. “Where’d you go, bud?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli told him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I remember you telling me about it,” Joshua murmured, and then said to himself, “A cabin up north huh? I could live with that.” He nudged Eli’s arm. “What do you say? Why don’t we get out of this stinking place? Head up north for a while and get a breath of fresh air?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli went on stroking his beard. After a while he said, “Yeah. Why not?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua laughed and nearly jumped to his feet, did the best he could. He clapped Eli’s shoulder. “Well how’s that? You’ve softened up in your old age, haven’t you? Let’s do it then; Tomorrow we’ll take Laurie upriver and go into town and…” He rambled on about what they’d need to do. They’d stop at the bank and get packed, buy some train tickets. Eli let him go on and on, and even allowed himself to get a little excited. It had been years since he’d been up to the cabin, but he knew his brother still used it from time to time, kept it in shape. Still, knowing him, there would be plenty to keep him busy up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, the two men both felt much more at ease by the time midnight rolled around, and drained, less from the labours of the day than the emotional toll, they retired for the night, headed below deck, and climbed into their hammocks. Before they were both asleep, Joshua said, “It is a shame, about that poor girl.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That it is,” Eli agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess we’re lucky to have lived as long as we have,” Joshua said, “It’s surprising, really, when you think about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I hope she’s found peace, wherever she is now,” Eli said, rolling over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Amen, old friend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few hours later, Eli awoke feeling sick and disoriented. He had sobered significantly and his throat felt dry and swollen. Trying to sit up, he realized that Joshua was grabbing his shoulder tightly. “What in the hell?” Eli said, whipping around, “What time is it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua put his finger to his lips. “Laurie’s on the move,” he hissed, “Can’t you hear it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was as though Joshua’s words unplugged his ears. The sound of the boat and of the river rushed into them. To be sure, they were on the move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How’s that possible?” Eli asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” Joshua replied, “Just grab your knife.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli did as Joshua instructed and quietly went to his trunk to fetch his large folding knife, another heirloom from his father. Joshua meanwhile grabbed a crowbar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ready?” Joshua asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess I am,” Eli answered. His head was still reeling from his interrupted sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pair poked their heads out from below deck and were surprised at the chill in the air and the brightness in the sky. It was enough to sting their eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clouds from earlier in the night had all dissipated, and the stars seemed to shine brighter than they ever had in those parts, but they were nothing compared to the heavy moon which hung low over the river, bathing it in ghostly light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Old Luna seems fit to burst,” Eli couldn’t help himself from saying. Joshua shushed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They climbed up the stairs and to the helm, shivering in the cold breeze. Eli thought about how sultry it had been only a few hours earlier. Outside the cabin door they stopped to ready themselves. Joshua gave a silent count and then they threw it open, weapons at the ready, only to find the place abandoned. They hesitated for a moment, stunned, then Joshua made his way to the helm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The thing’s stuck,” he said, “The motor won’t turn off either.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli peered out the window towards the stern and went pale. He pointed. “Look.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua did so, not seeing what it was Eli saw at first, but when he did he gasped. “That isn’t real,” he whispered. “It can’t be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She stood at the front of the riverboat, naked and pale in the moonlight. Her long blonde hair blew gently in the icy breeze as she stared forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly they descended onto the deck and approached her. Neither knew what to say. Both harboured a belief that they were simply dreaming, that the moment the dead girl turned to face them the horror of it would startle them awake, and yet the smell of the water and the bite of the cold wind aggressively told them that this was not the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing here?” Joshua finally had the nerve to ask. The question seemed bizarre even to him, but there was nothing else he could think to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turned to look over her shoulder, regarded them apathetically. She did not seem angry or sad, but nor did she seem happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please, leave us alone,” Eli called to her, trying to muster up a tone of authority, despite the shakiness in his voice. “We meant you no harm. We only tried to help.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think she means us harm either,” Joshua said, “Look.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was pointing now, a long, thin finger, pointing up river towards a strange glow on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think she’s taking us somewhere,” Joshua said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nowhere we want to be, that’s for damned sure,” Eli scowled. Frustrated, he began to shout, “Leave us be! You don’t belong here, spirit, and we aren’t going with you. Go on now!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl’s only reaction to his demands was a small smile. The corner of her lips curled into a knowing grin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is that?” Joshua asked, “Yonder. You see that, Eli? It looks like some kind of fog.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What little anger had temporarily blinded Eli from his fear quickly evaporated. The sight of that wall of fog one the river ahead chilled him sorely, but worse than that was the smell which suddenly hit him, the smell which he believed was coming from that obscuring fog. It was like wet earth and rot, sharp and sweet, but sickly. It turned his stomach, and at the same time filled him with a terrible weariness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve got no choice,” he said, “We’ve got to get off this boat. We’re going to have to jump overboard, come on.” He grabbed Joshua’s arm and tried to tug him starboard, but he resisted. “Josh, what are you doing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now hold on, Eli,” Joshua said, only half looking at him, “Aren’t you curious? I really don’t think she means us any harm. I think she just wants to show us something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli began to panic. “What are you talking about, Josh, we’ve got to go.” He tried to appeal to him in another way. “What about our trip? The cabin up north. Come on, Josh, I want to show you the streams we got up there, and the mountains. It’s beautiful, I’m telling you.” Just like before, these words, spoken for Joshua’s benefit, drew something genuine from deep inside of him and he began to ramble. “We’ll go fishing, just like we did back when we first got the idea to get this boat, and at night we’ll build a big fire and we’ll reminisce about the times we had. We’ll be able to rest, I promise you, we’ll take a break for as long as you want, just please,” he looked at his friend imploringly, “let’s get off this damned boat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua was no longer looking at Eli. He stared straight ahead through the girl, and into the fog which they were fast approaching. “I’ve got to know,” was all he said. “I’ve got to know what it’s all about.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli felt his eyes burn with tears. The smell of the fog, the smell of death, was overpowering, but still he could not release his friend. He choked back a sob and with one more futile tug pleaded, “It’s now or never, Josh.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua said nothing for a while. There was a serene look in his eyes. “I’m sorry, Eli.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli looked once more at the girl and watched as she was consumed by the moonlit fog. The final expression she showed him was the one he and his old friend had been waiting for when they first approached her, and it did wake him up, in a sense, though it was evidently too late for Joshua.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three heavy footfalls, a panicked leap over the railing, and Eli crashed into the water. He swam desperately for shore and managed to reach it just in time to look back and watch his boat and his best friend be consumed by the fog and disappear. He sat trembling, his mouth agape, and watched as the fog receded upriver, leaving no trace of Laurie and her captain. After a while the smell vanished as well, along with the chill in the air, then the bugs and the birds and the wetland critters took up their ceaseless chattering once more, as all the signs of life returned to Big River.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/what-they-found-on-Big-River&quot;&gt;What they found on Big River&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by P. Robbins at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;P. Robbins Writing&lt;/a&gt; on January 12, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dreams of Rain and Fire]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/dreams-of-rain-and-fire" />
  <id>/dreams-of-rain-and-fire</id>
  <published>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>P. Robbins</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Daniel came to mid-stride and nearly tripped over the curb. He stumbled into somebody, a large man, who subsequently pushed him away, cursing him out. The man’s breath reeked of booze. Daniel reeled for a moment, trying to grab hold of something which had just disappeared from within his grasp. The smell of smoke still filled his nose. The drunk took a swing at him and for moment his vision blurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel blinked. He felt his cheek pressed hard against a filthy curb and tried to lift it off, but a terrible splitting pain shot through his head. The drunk was gone, and those few who remained on that half-deserted street chose to pass him by. For a while he just breathed, trying to make sense of it all. With a trembling hand he touched his face, smeared the blood across his cheek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through no small effort, Daniel managed to pick himself up and stumble into an adjacent alley. Somewhere in the distance he could hear church bells and the rumble of thunder as he lowered himself back onto the ground, leaning against a dumpster for support. He tried to wipe the blood from his face, but only made a mess. Thankfully, the rain started to pour just then. It felt cool and fresh on his skin, skin, which he could recall with sickening clarity, that had just previously been burning in the heat of that terrible blaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tried to steady himself. He closed his eyes against the drops of water and let them wash the blood from his cheek, from his lip. Slowly his memories started to return to him. Yes, he’d been having trouble sleeping, he’d gone out to get some air. Or had he been sleep walking? In any case, where had he ended up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tried to stand. His head spun, but only for a moment. A nearby door opened, and he looked as a man in an apron stepped out to dump some trash. The man looked at Daniel suspiciously, but said nothing. Through the open door Daniel caught the sight of mangled bodies, the flayed skin, and the burnt flesh. He looked at the man once more. His face was round and greasy and there was a stubby cigar tucked into the corner of his yellowed mouth. He glared at Daniel. It was a face he recognized, though the man was undoubtedly a stranger. Daniel found himself reaching for a pistol that wasn’t there, panicked when he realized it. Without a word, the man with Johnson’s face stepped back into the building and shut the door on that bloody scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel hurried back toward the street. The rain was falling harder now. He tried to look for a street sign, but couldn’t find one. He thought of Johnson’s face, one of the faces in his dream. But those bodies… He shook his head, wiped the rain from his eyes. He knew he had to get back home, but where was home? An apartment, across from the church. He had heard the bells, but they were quiet know. The thunder still rolled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under a churning sky and swaying buildings, Daniel made his way up the narrow street passed grey pedestrians, their collars turned up against the bitter wind, and all the while felt like he was being watched. Twice he turned and thought he saw someone following him. With great relief the street he followed came to an intersection with a main street, filled with people. He stopped the first normal looking person who passed him by to ask where the church was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The church?” The pedestrian repeated, looking Daniel in the eye. Daniel gasped. “What are you looking for a church for, son? Got some confessing to do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The words he spoke came with a high pitched whistle, probably on account of his missing nose. It had been blown away by a bullet from behind him, along with one of his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m only joking,” Marlowe gurgled, blood running from his mouth, and he pointed behind Daniel. “You’ll just want to head down the road that way. Turn left on Church Street, it’s not far.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wet slap of Daniel’s shoes against the pavement was drowned, along with Marlowe’s words, by the murmur of the inattentive crowds. Daniel disappeared among the gathering of streetwalkers, heading in the direction he had been pointed, bumping into people as he stumbled along. The church bells sounded once more. He looked up, and above the nearby buildings he could see a lofty spire, peeking over them as it were. The bell sounded clear through the heavy pounding of the rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things started to return to Daniel. He could recognize where he was now, well enough. He took a turn and headed down the street towards his apartment building. The only thought he tried to hold onto was the thought of home. He pushed everything else aside, for the moment, the carnage, the familiar faces, and even the vague smell of smoke which still lingered around him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up the stairwell he hurried, losing his breath in the process. He ducked into his hallway, gasping, and for a moment panicked as he reached into his pocket for his keys. After some fumbling, he felt his fingertips brush against the cold, metal teeth. He fished the key up and opened the door. Slamming it behind him as he gulped at the familiar air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here he experienced a wave of relief. He felt safe, momentarily. As he scanned his room, his mind began to call up memories, and before long he was feeling like himself again. Though whether ‘himself’ was how he wanted to feel was another matter. The place was small, dingy. He had not cleaned in weeks, evidently. The bed he stood before was like a battlefield in a war against insomnia – the sheets were bunched, torn away from every corner, and his pillow looked like it had taken more than a couple beatings. By his nightstand were scattered bottle of sleeping pills, illicit and otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, he had had trouble sleeping alright. He had been experiencing walking dreams, nightmares – hallucinations, one supposes, but nothing like what he’d been encountering today. No, today it was like he couldn’t tell what was real and what wasn’t. It was enough to make him wonder if this wasn’t his dream right now, and that other place, the raging fire….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thought made him sweat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With shaky hands he reached for the bottle and poured himself a glass, spilling it slightly upon the already messy floor. He lifted the glass to his lips and took a pull, but as the pleasantly biting liquid rolled down his tongue, it changed to smoke. He closed his eyes and felt the glass between his thumb and forefinger itself change form. He was no longer drinking, but rather taking a drag from a cigarette. He opened his eyes, and he was in a bar with Johnson by his side, the ape of a man, with that cigar fixed to the corner of his mouth. He removed it only to take a gulp from his stein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What abut Marlowe?” Daniel found himself asking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’ll get what’s coming to him,” Johnson answered, his voice like the crunching of distant thunder. He patted the pistol on his hip. “More for us, eh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel felt hesitant. He looked around at the denizens of the establishment. It was a small but nevertheless diverse crowd. He and Johnson were certainly the most intimidating of the lot, and the others all refused to meet his stare. There was a family eating dinner at one end, a few travelling business men, it seemed, at another. Directly across the room from the bar where he and Johnson sat their mark: a nervous Roma and his haughty wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How do we even know he has it?” Daniel asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnson laughed softly. “Look at the fellow,” he said, “He’s got it. He keeps looking over here too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, you’re so ugly, who wouldn’t stare?” Daniel joked, but Johnson did not smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnson rose and immediately made a beeline for the foreigner and his wife. Daniel tried to get his attention with a silent gesture of protest, but it went unheeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good evening, sir,” Johnson said, and turning to his wife added, “Ma’am.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man grew pale. The wife, however, stared him in the eye. “What do you want?” She asked as she drummed her ring-laden fingers against the table. Her eyes were as black as her hair, which she wore in loose braids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I just couldn’t help but notice your husband looking over towards my friend and me, and I thought we might as well come over and introduce ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel noticed that the bar had gone silent. Everyone was listening to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s probably look at you because he knows you’re a killer,” the woman said, and then looking at Daniel directly added, “You and your friends, the both of them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something twitched in Johnson’s face. He gnawed on his cigar for a moment. “Now, that is quite the accusation to make, ma’am.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman’s husband was as still as a statue. He did not look at Daniel or Johnson, but rather kept his wide, horrified eyes fixed on his bold wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your soul is tainted. You’re a big man in this life, but your soul is small and more hideous than your face. If you keep living the way you do, you will know only tragedy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Johnson laughed. “A fortune-telling gypsy!” He declared. “Never heard of that! What, are you going to curse me next? What have I done to you anyhow?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s done is done,” the woman said, darkly, “I do not need to curse you, nor threaten you with the fires of hell. This world is a hell for people like you.” She turned sad then, and lowered her eyes at last. “Kill us or embrace us, what’s done is done.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one moved. No one said a word. Even the hovering smoke which filled the room seemed to be stilled by the tension. Then everyone turned as one of the floorboards at the top of the stairs creaked. Down stumbled Marlowe, his eyes all red and weepy. He had been sleeping off a raging a drunk. He walked heavily down the steps until the silence presumably touched his ears. He stopped and stared as everyone watched him. With some alarm he noticed who Johnson had, apparently, been speaking to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Marlowe!” Johnson said, staring back at him. “Fetch us some whisky. I think I’d like to have a drink with our new friends here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hesitantly, Marlowe did as he was bid, wiping his face nervously. The second his back was to Johnson, however, Johnson drew his pistol and fired. Someone screamed as Marlowe fell to the ground, blood rushing from his head across the barroom floor. The scream seemed, to Daniel, to come from somewhere far away, drawing closer, and closer, until the sound was like a siren, splitting his ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He blinked and watched as the flashing lights of an ambulance rushed down the street. He was outside again, thought the rain had lightened a bit. It was almost dark. He whipped around as the siren passed, ready to fight, ready to do something, disoriented as the world spun around his head. He cried out, “God! What’s happening to me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took him another moment to recompose himself. A few who passed him by watched him wordlessly, though only for a moment each. Something, however, told him that he was being watched continuously. He looked around him and sure enough, further down the street, someone stood and stared at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” he muttered and began to walk in the other direction which, luckily for him, was back towards his home. “Why do I keep coming out this way?” He asked himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His sense of direction was better now, and he realized he hadn’t gone far, though he’d apparently been out long enough to get soaked to the bone. He just needed to get back inside, get warm and dry. He would stay awake, if he had to, he told himself, though a kind of hopelessness was beginning to spread through his body in the form of a terrible inertia. He was heading towards something, he felt, and this would not be over until he reached where he was going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon he was at the church, and for a moment, grasping for any kind of meaning, he stopped. He looked towards his apartment building and then back to the church. The bells rang suddenly, startling him, and he turned quickly and could see that the figure he had seen before had followed him all the way to the church. Without a second thought, fear welling up in his throat, he dashed inside, the bells still ringing loudly overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the church, the air changed from moist to musty. The murmur of the crowds died away, and the sound of the rainfall, harsh upon the pavement, turned into a kind of light pitter-patter, not unlike the sound of fingers drumming against a table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holding his head between his hands, he made his way up towards the alter, the heavy cross beyond. He fell to his knees and began to weep softly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Excuse me,” a slightly nervous voice sounded from near the entrance. “Excuse me, sir, are you alright?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel turned around slightly. It was a priest calling to him. He rose and started to walk towards him, unable to find the words to express his current plight. The priest stood where he was as Daniel approached him, and as his face became clearer to him Daniel began to recognized him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“God, no,” he muttered to himself, tired of it all. The face of the barman, suspended over the priest’s collar, stared back at him bewildered. “Please,” Daniel said as he approached, faster and faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He reached for his pistol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The barman had a shotgun in his hands but Daniel had the drop on him. Someone was still screaming, and now Daniel could feel Marlowe’s blood soaking into his old, worn shoes. Johnson was yelling something, but Daniel couldn’t make it out. He turned slightly to hear and that was when the barman made his move. Daniel pulled the trigger, almost without thinking, and the man went down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everyone out!” Johnson was yelling. “Get the hell out of here, right now.” He was pointing his gun at the man and his wife. “Not you two. Come on, we’re going up to your room. No more fooling around. You know what we’re here for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man was shaking like a leaf. The woman simply looked dejected. Daniel followed her gaze to the body of Marlowe in his pool of blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on, you too, ma’am,” Johnson said, and then with a smile added, “It’s just as you said. I’m a killer, so you know I’m not playing. Let’s get a move on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Johnson,” Daniel said, “What the hell. You said we weren’t going to do it here. We had a plan!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well,” Johnson laughed, as he shoved the barrel of his pistol between the man’s shoulder blades. “Plan’s changed. Might as well get it all over with, eh? You get the lady.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel’s ears were ringing. He turned to the woman who was now staring at him, her eyes a mix of disgust and sorrow. He gestured with his gun. “You heard the man,” he said to her, trying to keep the shakiness from his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She rose without a word, and the two of them followed Johnson and her husband up the stairs. Then they were in their room and the man was taking the suitcase out from underneath the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hand it over, my friend,” Johnson said. The man did as he was told. Keep his gun on the man with one hand, Johnson opened the case with the other and looked inside. He grinned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is it there?” Daniel asked, without looking away at the woman, whose eyes were fixed upon him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, yes,” Johnson said, “Boss’ll be happy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know about that,” Daniel replied, wiping the sweat from his eye, “I killed the barman.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Of course you did,” Johnson said, shutting the case, “You had no choice. He shot Marlowe!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fiends!” The woman snarled. “Your boss is Satan himself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnson’s smiled began to fade. He sighed. Daniel, who was still looking directly at the woman jumped when he heard the gunshot. He turned. Her husband was on the floor, bleeding from his belly, choking on the blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now her pride crumbled. Her composure was shattered. She wailed, and the sound was awful to Daniel’s ears. “Johnson!” He shouted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on, kid, let’s get out of here,” the large man said as the woman threw herself on her husband. He removed the cigar from his mouth and tossed it on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wails of the woman followed them as they descended the stairs. Neither said a word as they stepped into the carnage below. Daniel hurried for the door, but Johnson stayed behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing?” Daniel asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnson, as though in reply, pulled a couple of bottles from behind the counter, uncorked them, and began dumping the contents on the bar, splashing some on the curtains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, you know me, Daniel,” he said then, pulling a fresh cigar out of his pocket. “I can’t help myself. It’s an addiction.” He produced a lighter, flicked it open, and lit his cigar, taking a long, satisfying draw, before tossing the still lit lighter. With a loud poof, the flame went up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a breeze against Daniel’s cheek. He blinked at the darkness before him. Slowly his eyes began to adjust. He was in the park and the rain had picked up again. It was now falling in heavy sheets across the empty greenery. He was far away from home now, and yet a kind of peacefulness filled him. Beyond the darkness he could see the figure who had been falling him. She approached him now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her eyes were as dark as her hair which hang loose and wet upon her shoulders. She looked at him only with pity now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kill us or embrace us,” she said, “what’s done is done.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel trembled as the cold rain fell hard upon his head. He felt as though he were swimming in some vast, freezing ocean. She came to him with arms outstretched. He tried to close his eyes, but the shutting of his eyelids was like the opening of a pair of curtains, unveiling a new scene: The public house was burning, a tower of flame. He and Johnson were standing before it, feeling the heat of the blaze upon their cheeks. In the doorway she emerged, naked, dressed in fire, her arms open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shut his eyes again, again unveiling another scene. She stood in the darkness, rain soaked, arms open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shut his eyes. He now approached her, walking into the unbearable heat of the blaze. Johnson was shouting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shut his eyes. The cold wind cut at his face. He was being torn apart, but he knew that in her arms he’d find peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shut his eyes. She wrapped her arms around him as the arch of the doorway collapsed, spilling fire over both of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shut his eyes. She dragged him into the wet, cold earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shut his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/dreams-of-rain-and-fire&quot;&gt;Dreams of Rain and Fire&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by P. Robbins at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;P. Robbins Writing&lt;/a&gt; on January 06, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Monster of Shelby Cove]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/The-Monster-of-Shelby-Cove" />
  <id>/The-Monster-of-Shelby-Cove</id>
  <published>2018-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2018-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>P. Robbins</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>patrick@probbinswriting.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fish bones line the beach tread upon by portly tourists. They snap pictures of the cove, peaceful and deadly beneath a grey sky. Sputtering rain comes and goes, and Lawrence Murphy plays with a bit of seashell while he drinks whisky and watches the churning of the sky. It’s been a month since he lost his boy, a week since his wife went away. He’s only got Old Tommy and his fiddle for company, but there is no cause for music now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great jawbone of a shark hangs over his window, gaping at him, its teeth sharp and white. Was his boy torn apart by such a creature? Or was it something else? Did he drown, as Maggie suggested with certainty bordering on mania? He takes a sip of Scotch from his mug as Old Tommy returns from the store, plastic bags in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tommy fixes them sandwiches, but Lawrence can’t eat. He just goes on drinking, grappling with some thought. Tommy can tell they are coming to a moment – one of those irrevocable revelations which result in a decision that changes everything. It’s as though Lawrence wrestles with the monster itself, down below those black waves, and can feel its strength slipping in his grasp. He is within reach of something. Perhaps before dark he will subdue the beast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark is coming on fast, though. Storm clouds threaten the tourists down by the shore. Only a few god-rays manage to break through and glitter on the waves. Lawrence hears one of the men on the beach let out a holler. He has seen the monster of Shelby Cove, like so many before. How many Polaroids, snapshots from disposable cameras, recordings on camcorders otherwise used at family Christmas gatherings, thanksgiving dinners; How many had obtained proof of the monster, out there on the cove?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For thirty years Lawrence has lived by the shore. He has always been a believer. Gullible by nature, Maggie used to tease. He has seen the monster once though, when he was eighteen – only a few years older than Lochlin. It had been a dark night – no moon to light the waves, only a kind of glow on the horizon: Twilight. There was nothing which terrified Lawrence more than the sea at twilight. The water, obscured by the darkness, becomes like a door leading into a pitch black room, but you know that in the room squats something awful, something with a mouth the size of a small person, perhaps a boy, and deep-sea eyes which stare, alien, uncaring, yet full of some mystifying arcane knowledge. The monster was as old as time. Perhaps, Lawrence thought, it was the leviathan in the bible, or one of its dread offspring that had wandered to this part of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his dreams he can sometimes see it, rising out of the water, opening its hideous mouth. Graveyard breath; A translucent belly full of the bones of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were those pseudo-scientists who sometimes came to town, filming an episode of some cable TV show about various urban myths and legends, and some not-so-urban ones. Lawrence has heard every possible explanation, from ridiculous to plausible – Plesiosaur, Oarfish, mutant shark. Then there was the history, sightings which supposedly went back as far as to the pioneer times, some claimed earlier, with Old Indian tales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawrence finishes what was in his mug and gets up to refill it. Tommy says something, but he cannot hear. He regards his face in a mirror on the wall – old, haggard, eyes red like a sunset. He empties what’s left in the bottle into his mug and returns to his rocking chair by the window, beneath the sharks maw. There is lightning on the horizon, chains of electricity which crackle on the seeming edge of the world. It drives forth something in the air, collides with the shoreline like some invisible wave which sends a tingle across Lawrence’s skin. Goose pimples erupt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his dreams he is eighteen, out on the water in his rowboat, not too far from shore but far enough that in the darkness he might pretend as though he was in the middle of the sea. He is alone, a little drunk. He brings in the oars and sits there a while, taking in the growing dark, the eerie twilight. There is a thrill to it all. Then he hears the bump from beneath his feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something brushes against the boat – once, twice, a third time. It is a kind of skidding bump, like something long running against it. He freezes, and detects a kind of sound coming from the water, not unlike the whale song, but harsher on the ear, despite how quiet it sounds. There is another bump, harder this time, against the side of the boat. It feels deliberate, and young Lawrence’s mind is filled with images of staved boats. One more bump now, this time lighter, definitely deliberate. It is almost as if something is tapping the side of his boat, beckoning him to peer over the edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether out of morbid curiosity, or some stranger compulsion, Lawrence always looks. In his dream recollection, he tries to resist, but feels a terrible certainty that should he try to deny the creatures invitation, it will rip his boat in half and then tear him to pieces in its teeth. It only wants to reveal itself to him, that is all, and so it will. Lawrence peers over the edge of the boat and sees the horror just beneath the water. The eyes, dead, yet full of comprehension, the mouth, lined with angler-fish teeth, bent into a hateful grin – demon fish, face of a monster, he regards it and, to his terrible fear, it regards him, it rises up out of the water and opens its mouth, unhinging its jaw, as though to speak, and that is when he hears the noise again – like the collective moan of a crowd of people trapped in some sinking boat. The sound rattles his skull and he awakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, he rises before Tommy and heads into town to buy more booze. The sky is still overcast, but even so he shields his eyes by tugging his cap down over them. He goes to the general store where he receives a few woeful glances from townsfolk. Everyone has heard by this point that Maggie has packed her bags and headed back to her parents’. Mike, who runs the counter, rings Lawrence up and looks as though he wants to say something, but Lawrence ignores him, and he shuts his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottle in hand, wrapped in brown, he heads back up the hill, but his eye wanders, as it always does, to Harold’s shop. He has not been inside there since what happened to Lochlin, but this does not mean he doesn’t peek. Today, there is something of a gathering in there. Nothing surprising about that. Whenever a new bus-load of tourists show up, they inevitably end up in Harold’s for some souvenirs, or perhaps a bit of a history lesson from the man himself, a once good friend of Lawrence’s. Now, though, this is different. He sees a couple of tourists, to be sure, but the majority of the crowd he recognizes as locals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is just like his dreams. Something compels him, like a siren song, to go closer, to look over the edge of the boat, to step in through the door. The ring of the bell brings a few eyes his way. There is a double take as one of the locals realizes who’s just entered, but the rest are much too fixated on something. There are whispers and murmurs, one of which is directed to Harold who quickly looks up and sees Lawrence. He seems afraid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lawrence,” he says, and impatiently adds, “What are you doing here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s going on?” Lawrence asks, his voice a croak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing. You shouldn’t be here,” is what Harold tries to say, but he is cut off by another man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re trying to tell if this photo is legitimate!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An argument kicks up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I took it last night!” One of the tourists, an older gentleman, exclaims, “And besides, I wouldn’t know the first thing about altering no photograph.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“S’far as we know,” mumbles one of the locals, “Give it here, again, I wanna take another look.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture is passed around, but Lawrence can’t get a good look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Really, Lawrence, you know how it is,” Harold starts, “just another bit of so-called proof. Nothing you ain’t seen before.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time, Lawrence thought, that him and Harold had themselves poured over such pictures and recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t look like any fish I’ve ever seen. Don’t look much like a fish at all. Ugly sumbitch though.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some men laugh, but in a nervous kind of way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Give it to me,” Lawrence says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, you best be getting on home, to your…” Harold trails off, “Well, you best be getting on home anyhow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, give it here,” Lawrence says, and one of the tourists hands him the photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t!” Harold exclaims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The face of the monster. Those pale eyes – ghost-like beneath the surface – that nightmare smile, transparent teeth through which can be seen an abyss like no other. He drops the picture and staggers for the door while men call after him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By noon Lawrence is in a drunken stupor, asleep in his bed, half the bottle emptied into his guts, his brain. He snores softly, his body tense. Old Tommy watches him from the doorway, then goes outside to play his fiddle: a sad song. The sky begins to leak and the waves on the sea crash hard upon the rocks below. The beach is deserted today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawrence is dreaming. Beneath those violent waves he rows a staved boat. Dark, boiling water surrounds him and he can hear it: beyond the current, the sound from the belly of the beast, the groans of the dead. One voice in particular wails to him, forcing him to row faster, only he can’t tell if he’s rowing away or towards it. A flash of lightning illuminates the water and he can see the shape of the monster swirling about beneath the troubled surface, twisting itself into some violent shape, some eternal Oroboros. At the centre lies the face, staring at him. Eyes like full moons suspended over the gaping, ravenous mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His ears are filled with water and the moaning of the countless slain – slaughtered Indians, old pilgrims who never found their new Eden, whalers and merchant sailors lost at sea, bathers: men, women, children; Lochlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dad.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Lawrence awakes it is evening. His head swims, his stomach crawls. Slowly the world takes shape around him, and before long he is weeping. Outside his door, Old Tommy sits and listens, but does nothing, can do nothing. Likewise, as he watches when Lawrence emerges from his room and puts on his sweater, grabs an old lantern. For a moment, their eyes meet and Old Tommy sees in his friends a pain that he cannot begin to describe let alone understand. He says not a word as Lawrence steps out and heads down to the docks, towards the rowboat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once, when Old Tommy was young, he liked to read philosophy. He got a bit of a reputation as a local wise man which only grew as he aged and became more reticent. People seemed to take his silence for quiet understanding, though the truth was simply that the older he got, the less he understood. So it was that he couldn’t bring himself to help his young friend Lawrence, for as he watched him sink into annihilation he could think of no bit of wisdom that could ease the mans burden. On the contrary, Old Tommy found himself tormented by a thought, something he had read about years ago: The Eternal Return – the idea that we are born into the same life again and again, forced to repeat the events of our lives without end, unable to change them, unable, even, to remember them. So it would be, that Lawrence, who will die this night at sea will be born again in Shelby’s Cove, will grow up to meet Maggie. They will fall in love, get married, and Maggie will give birth to a beautiful baby boy named Lochlin. They will watch with pleasure as the baby grows into a boy and then into a kind young man, until once again his raft washes to shore in pieces bringing with it a cloud as black as a starless midnight in the middle of the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to will Lawrence, again and again, depart his home and fix the lantern to his boat, take the oars and row it out onto the temporarily quiet and peaceful sea as twilight falls. He will row until the shore vanishes and then he’ll stop, and as the storm clouds gather, blotting out the fading afterglow of the setting sun he will cry out into the darkness, “Take me! Take me, you bastard! I’m here! I’m waiting for you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there will be moans on the waves; He will hear them at least, and he will smell the reek of bones and seaweed – a deep sea coffin – and perhaps, at last, he will even see those pale eyes he saw so many years ago. In the end, though, there will only be his cries and the answer in the wind of the rising storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take me! Take me Goddamn you!”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/The-Monster-of-Shelby-Cove&quot;&gt;The Monster of Shelby Cove&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by P. Robbins at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;P. Robbins Writing&lt;/a&gt; on December 25, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>